<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wesley Tian</title>
    <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Wesley Tian</description>
    <generator>Hugo - gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <contact>tian.wesley@gmail.com</contact>
    <copyright>&copy; Wesley Tian 2019</copyright>
    
        <atom:link href="https://wesleytian.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Climbing the Tallest Mountain in the Contiguous US</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/whitney/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/whitney/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/whitney/whitney_sunrise.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;
title=&#34;I did not take this picture.&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;Mount Whitney &amp;ldquo;The Big Daddy&amp;rdquo; (14,505 ft / 4,421 m)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;day-1-mountain-view-to-lone-pine&#34;&gt;Day 1: Mountain View to Lone Pine&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/whitney/jeep.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;
title=&#34;The perfect ride.&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/whitney/map_route.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;
title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On August 6th, 2019, Douglas Qian, Newton Xie, Noriyuki Kojimano and I set out from Mountain View, CA to climb Mount Whitney, the tallest mountain in the contiguous United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;day-2-acclimatization-at-lone-pine-lake&#34;&gt;Day 2: Acclimatization at Lone Pine Lake&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading about &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Altitude_sickness&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;altitude sickness&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High-altitude_cerebral_edema&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;high-altitude cerebral edema&lt;/a&gt; which could permanently damage your brain and lead to death terrified the hell out of us. Acclimating by resting at a higher altitude for a while seemed like a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/whitney/lone_pine_lake.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;
title=&#34;Serene af.&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/whitney/lone_pine_group.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;
title=&#34;From left, Doug, Wes, Newton, Nori&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;Lone Pine Lake (10,050 ft / 3,063 m)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we hiked the 5.2-mile loop to the lake. We stayed at the lake for a couple of hours to help with the acclimatization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the ascent, we heard and saw lightning from many directions so we were afraid that would jeopardize our summit day plans. Besides the effects of altitude sickness, the most dangerous thing that could happen in this area is being struck by lightning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-1990-07-16-mn-100-story.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; following story headlined the news,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;LONE PINE, Calif. —
As lightning lacerated the darkening sky over Mt. Whitney and thunderclaps started a deafening roll, the 13 hikers saw the old stone hut with its corrugated metal roof as a welcome refuge from the drenching downpour.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
It nearly became their tomb.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
“I was sitting on the floor, my back against one of the walls,” said Edward (E.J.) Wueherer, a hiker from Tehachapi. “All of a sudden I saw this flash and I felt this jolt like on my funny bone, and my toe started burning.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
“The next thing I knew I was helping to untangle bodies.”
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The surging electrical charge threw Matthew Edward Nordbrock, who had been seated in the center of the hut, several feet, where he lay still on the ground.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
As the hikers had sprinted for cover during the squall Saturday afternoon, Nordbrock, 26, of Huntington Beach, told one of his hiking buddies: “I’ve been hit by lightning before, so I won’t get struck.”
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
He died several hours later, after being removed from the 14,495-foot summit by helicopter.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;day-3-the-big-day&#34;&gt;Day 3: The Big Day&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went to bed around 8:00 p.m. that night and set our alarms for 2 a.m., but anxious to start the climb, we naturally woke up around 1:00 a.m. We arrived at the Mount Whitney trailhead around 2:00 a.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/whitney/start.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;
title=&#34;From left, Doug, Wes, Nori, Newton&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;2:15 a.m. – Mile 0: Mount Whitney trailhead (8,360 ft / 2,548 m)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a few hours, we navigated the mountain trail by relying completely on our trusty headlamps. We strained our ears for signs of a thunderstorm which would&amp;rsquo;ve stopped our hike cold and saddened us deeply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/whitney/night_crossing.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;
title=&#34;From left, Wes, Newton&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;Stream crossing&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a couple of streams that we had to cross, but they were quite manageable and my feet were never wet beyond my toes. We scheduled periodic snack breaks every 1.5 hours and took breaks and filtered water as needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/whitney/sunrise.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;
title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;5:42 a.m. – Sunrise&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few hours of hiking in complete darkness, we began to see the faint glow of the rising sun. Our hearts shrank as we saw the dark clouds in the distance. There were few people on the trail and was it felt unnaturally serene as there was no wildlife. At that moment, I felt like we were the only living things alive in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/whitney/whitney.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;
title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The sky looks clear!&amp;rdquo; I shouted in relief as I realized that the clouds we saw earlier were just mountains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We continued to set our hopes high, but also kept our expectations low to avoid potential disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw a lot more people as we neared the trail camp. Unlike us knuckleheads, most sane people take on this mountain in many days. We enviously watched as groups of well-rested, fully acclimated backpackers packed up their tents, prepared warm breakfasts, and readied themselves to tackle the summit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/whitney/trail_camp.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;
title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;5:58 a.m. – Mile 6: Trail Camp (12,039 ft, 3,669 m)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the last place to get water according to both online and local sources. One person told us that we only needed to bring 1.5L to 2L of water–which we realized didn&amp;rsquo;t make sense only after it was too late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 liters of water got me to trail camp and the route to trail camp was only a quarter of the entire trail. From trail camp to summit and back to trail camp was around half of the entire trail, so at the very least we should have brought 4L of water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also marked the beginning of the infamous &amp;ldquo;97-switchbacks&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/whitney/switchbacks.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Switchbacks&#34;
title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;Some of the switchbacks&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/whitney/trail_crest.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Start of the Trail Crest&#34;
title=&#34;Doug&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;Mile 8.7: Start of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Trail_Crest&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Trail Crest&lt;/a&gt; (13,645 ft / 4,159 m), the highest trail pass in the US&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/whitney/trail_crest_west.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Trail Crest&#34;
title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;8:45 a.m – Looking west from the Trail Crest&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still more than a half-hour from the summit and more than five miles to our next water source, Doug realized he was out of water. Hiking without water at such an altitude was a recipe for disaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My summer at CEO Satya Nadella&amp;rsquo;s Microsoft taught me a great deal about &amp;ldquo;growth mindset&amp;rdquo; and trying new things, so I jokingly suggested, &amp;ldquo;Hey guys, let&amp;rsquo;s just drink our piss!&amp;rdquo; We had filters anyways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect them to take me seriously, but Newton was actually like, &amp;ldquo;Sure.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, Newton, being the next to piss, pissed into one of our filter bottles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/whitney/piss.png&#34; alt=&#34;Trail Crest&#34;
title=&#34;Newton&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Iconic, dude.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not yet ready to become Bear Grylls, Doug responded, &amp;ldquo;Hell no!&amp;rdquo; when offered the piss-filtered water. Newton, being a true friend, ended up giving the rest of the water from his bottle to Doug and drank the filtered piss himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When asked what the water tasted like, Newton though for a second, furrowed his brows and said, &amp;ldquo;It didn&amp;rsquo;t taste like water. It tasted a bit bitter.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who knew?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/whitney/towards_summit.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Summit&#34;
title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;9:37 a.m. – Mile 9: Looking east at the summit from the Trail Crest&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was around this point that acute mountain sickness began to seriously impact our performance. Even with the two previous days of acclimatization, Nori&amp;rsquo;s heartrate remained a steady 180 BPM while running out of breath consistently, Newton felt nauseous and wanted to puke, and we all had the worst headaches of our entire lives. &lt;br&gt;
Every single step I took, I felt my head throbbing and pulsating with blood.  &lt;br&gt;
Every. &lt;br&gt;
Single.  &lt;br&gt;
Step. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step.  &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throb. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Step.  &lt;br&gt;
On the outside, I had my usual deadpan face, but internally I was screaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/whitney/snowfield.png&#34; alt=&#34;Snowfield&#34;
title=&#34;Wesley&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;10:22 a.m. – The snowfield before the summit&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no way that we would come this far to turn back now. Giving up was not an option. Even though we were all in pain, Doug and I kept yelling words of encouragement such as &amp;ldquo;We got this!&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re almost there!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confronting the altitude sickness, harsh winds, and the near-zero temperatures, we trudged onwards and eventually made it to the summit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/whitney/summit_group.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;
title=&#34;From left, Nori, Doug, Wes, Newton&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;11:09 a.m. – Mile 10.7: Mount Whitney summit (14,505 ft / 4,421 m)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;YEEEAAAAA&amp;rdquo; I screamed with the little energy I had left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had finally made it to the summit. To celebrate, Doug and I had some refreshing beers. In hindsight, consuming alcohol at the summit might not have been the smartest idea as it slows down the acclimatization process and dehydrates you, but YOLO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/whitney/beer.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Having a drink at the summit&#34;
title=&#34;Tangerine Express IPA&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;Enjoying a well-deserved drink&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few pictures in, Nori mentioned to us, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t feel good.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doug and I didn&amp;rsquo;t take this as seriously as we should have. His tone didn&amp;rsquo;t sound urgent to us and we wanted to take as many pictures as we could. Doug showed little symptoms of altitude sickness and I had a headache that was quickly disappearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few more minutes later, Nori said, this time more seriously, &amp;ldquo;Hey guys, can we head down soon?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By that point, we should have noticed that something was up, but we continued chatting with other hikers and went about our own business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few more minutes passed and this time Nori interjected our conversation and sternly demanded, &amp;ldquo;We need to go down. &lt;strong&gt;NOW&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only this time it hit us how urgent this situation was and I told Nori to immediately head down first, with Newton accompanying him. Only later did Nori tell us how much discomfort he was in. This event made me realize how subjective our experiences are and why it matters so much to be open to the subtle hints that other people give you. This could&amp;rsquo;ve turned out badly and I&amp;rsquo;m so glad it didn&amp;rsquo;t. Some extra few pictures aren&amp;rsquo;t worth the suffering of a fellow pal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way down, Doug and I thankfully found a few sources of water that we could filter on the way down so that we didn&amp;rsquo;t have to drink more piss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The summit is only halfway.&lt;/strong&gt; Descending wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy until we got a second wind when some hikers told us about the best burger ever at the Whitney Portal Store. Picturing fat juicy burgers in our heads, we immediately began running down the mountain to make it to the store before it closed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doug wanted the burger so bad that he was willing to further damage his knee to take a bite of the delicious burger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get the burgers before the store closed, Netwon offered to stay with Doug while he asked Nori and me to run down the remaining 5 miles of the mountain trail to get the burgers. We made it down in record time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What better motivation than food?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/whitney/burger.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Having a drink at the summit&#34;
title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;6:00 p.m. – Mile 22: The best burger ever&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In total, the hike took just under 16 hours. What a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;was-it-worth-it&#34;&gt;Was it worth it?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definitely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This hike may be the hardest non-technical day-hike in the contiguous US. (Technical hikes require the use of hands, usually involving mountaineering equipment such as ice axes and crampons.) At the very least, it&amp;rsquo;s the tallest. The hike wasn&amp;rsquo;t technical at all. I remember only having to use my hands twice, when there were icy rocks on the switchbacks and when I slipped coming down on the snowfield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though it was a long hike, anyone who is somewhat athletic and has good cardiovascular health should be able to conquer this mountain. Training will vary from person to person. A few months before this, I trained for a marathon at a 3:30 to 4:00 pace and I did a 10+ mile trek in Washington state. I also did some targeted work on my calves, side glutes, and hip flexors because of some muscle imbalances. Besides having also trained for and ran a marathon a few months prior, Doug didn&amp;rsquo;t do any extra training for the hike and was also fine. None of us felt anything besides some slight soreness the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hardest part of the hike was the symptoms of altitude sickness. Only Advil made the altitude sickness bearable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-s-next&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s next?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two routes I can take. I can either stick with non-technical hikes and start doing multi-day hikes, or I can start doing technical hikes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More challenging non-technical hikes include &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mount_Kilimanjaro&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mount Kilimanjaro&lt;/a&gt; (19,341 ft / 5,895 m) in Tanzania, Africa or &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aconcagua&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mount Aconcagua&lt;/a&gt; (22,837 ft / 6,960 m) in Argentina, South America. Both of these are part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seven_Summits&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Seven Summits&lt;/a&gt;, which are now on my radar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/whitney/seven_summits.png&#34; alt=&#34;Having a drink at the summit&#34;
title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, I could start learning technical mountaineering skills such as self-arrest with an ice ax and begin to do technical climbs such as on &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mount_Rainier&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mount Rainier&lt;/a&gt; (14,111 ft / 4,392 m).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever I choose, this hike has done a poor job at deterring me from more challenging hikes and only has me craving more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;my-complete-packing-list-42&#34;&gt;My Complete Packing List&amp;#42;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the beer, bring all the following and only the following. Avoid any non-essentials not listed to reduce weight. This packing list is only for the day-hikers. Multi-day summits will need extra gear such as a tent, sleeping bag, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
 &lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt;
 What to Wear&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moisture-Wicking T-shirt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pants &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rei.com/product/134025/prana-stretch-zion-straight-pants-mens&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;(Prana Stretch Zion Straight Pants)&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#42;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Socks &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rei.com/product/138105/darn-tough-hiker-no-show-light-cushion-socks-mens&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;(Darn Tough Hiker No-Show Light Cushion Socks)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shoes &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rei.com/product/134977/altra-lone-peak-4-trail-running-shoes-mens&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;(Altra Lone Peak 4 Trail-Running Shoes)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hiking Poles &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rei.com/product/127496/black-diamond-distance-carbon-flz-trekking-poles-pair&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;(Black Diamond Carbon FLZ Trekking Poles)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;~20L Backpack &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rei.com/product/111296/osprey-talon-22-pack-mens&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;(Osprey Talon 22 Pack)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mount Whitney Permit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt;
 Extra Clothes to Pack&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windbreaker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rain Jacket&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Synthetic Down Jacket&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fleece Jacket&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extra pair of socks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sunglasses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
 &lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt;
 Food &amp;amp; Water&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5L of Water, 3L Total Capacity&amp;#42;&amp;#42;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1500+ Calories of Food – You will burn over 4000 calories on this trip!&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beer&amp;#42;&amp;#42;&amp;#42;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt;
Other Essential Items&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;First Aid Kit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rei.com/product/800721/adventure-medical-kits-ultralightwatertight-3-medical-kit&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;(Adventure Medical Kits Ultralight/Watertight .3 Medical Kit)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Water Filter &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rei.com/product/100537/katadyn-befree-collapsible-water-filter-bottle-20-fl-oz&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;(Katadyn BeFree Collapsible Water Filter Bottle 1L)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pocket Knife &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swissarmy.com/us/en/Products/Swiss-Army-Knives/Medium-Pocket-Knives/Hiker/p/1.4613&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;(Victorinox Hiker Swiss Army Knife)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lip Balm with SPF&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sunscreen&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;WAGbag – The anywhere toilet kit&amp;#42;&amp;#42;&amp;#42;&amp;#42;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Map&amp;#42;&amp;#42;&amp;#42;&amp;#42;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#42;My recommendations are in parentheses. &lt;br&gt;
&amp;#42;&amp;#42;The amount of water you bring depends on the mountain water conditions and the time of year. Check with the park ranger or with recent hikers through &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/30962451768/about/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AllTrails&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/30962451768/about/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mt. Whitney Facebook Group&lt;/a&gt; to see how much water you should be bringing. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#42;&amp;#42;&amp;#42; Bring and drink at your own risk. &lt;br&gt;
&amp;#42;&amp;#42;&amp;#42;&amp;#42;You will be given one of these for each person in your group when you pick up your permit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/whitney/whitney_intro.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Having a drink at the summit&#34;
title=&#34;Til next time!&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or need any tips about the hike, feel free to reach out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, do your research and take everything with a grain of salt. Personal experiences are very subjective. If you want to summit Mount Whitney, start preparing before February of that year since the permit lottery happens during that time. The hardest part may actually be getting a permit since the acceptance rate is about 30%. Overnight permits are even rarer.
See &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/california/mount-whitney-via-mount-whitney-trail&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mount Whitney via Mount Whitney Trail on AllTrails&lt;/a&gt; for more information about the trail.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Had a 1.95 GPA in High School</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/gpa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/gpa/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t believe in yourself, nobody else will. – Me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my junior year of high school, when everybody else was trying the hardest that they have ever tried, I was on the verge of being put on academic probation. I ended the first semester of junior year with a 1.95 / 4.00 GPA. For those who aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with the GPA scale, 1.95 is equal to a C- (73%-70%).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/gpa/transcript.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;High school junior year transcript&#34;
    title=&#34;I wasn&#39;t kidding.&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;My official high school transcript.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I applied to college with a 2.92 GPA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To put that into perspective, the average GPA for University of Michigan&amp;rsquo;s accepted class in 2018 was 3.88.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and fun fact, I also got a 1 (failing score) on the AP Computer Science exam and my computer science teacher told me that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t fit to be a programmer. Even so, I never stopped believing that my future self would pick it up and turn my life around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will split this post into two sections. Section one will be about why my GPA was so terrible. Section two will be about what I learned from this experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-was-my-gpa-so-bad&#34;&gt;Why Was My GPA So Bad?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was first introduced to a game called League of Legends around the end of my freshman year. Soon after I started playing, I became well-known in my school as being one of the worst League of Legends players in the grade. It was a popular game at my school and people often made fun of me for how bad I was. Like being the class-clown, it was somewhat fun getting attention this way, but deep down, it didn&amp;rsquo;t feel very nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was around that point when I decided that I would stop at nothing to become one of the best players out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the 25 million players, I was stuck at the bottom 3% of them for two years. I was in what they called &amp;ldquo;Elo hell&amp;rdquo; (Elo is the name of the player ranking system. It&amp;rsquo;s the same ranking that chess players use.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/gpa/hell.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;
    title=&#34;Talk about being bad.&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt;The lowest possible Elo was around 500. The highest was 2500. &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began to spend more and more time on improving my game mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had many serious fights with my parents during this time due to my falling grades. I skipped classes and slept through exams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My parents, counselors, and teachers became concerned for me and tried all sorts of measures to control my computer usage. I was so addicted to getting better at the game that I threatened my parents that I would kill myself if they continued to try to restrict my life. By the start of my junior year, my parents gave up on me and gave me complete freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people are shocked that my parents would do that. My mom told me recently that it was because she believed in me and that if I did learn a lesson from all this, it would have to come from within. She was right and I am grateful for her beyond words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly two years later, I finally ended up in the top 2% of players in the world. I finally became better than all my peers at League of Legends. But, my GPA suffered as a result. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy. I stayed up till 4 AM on weekdays even when I had swim practice at 6 AM. I practiced my game mechanics for 10 continuous hours on the weekends and spent an estimated total of more than 1500 hours on the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason why my GPA was so bad in high school is simple. I spent all my time trying to become better than my peers at League of Legends. (And I finally did it.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/gpa/d5.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;
    title=&#34;Diamond 5&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;dream-big-and-never-stop-believing-in-yourself&#34;&gt;Dream Big and Never Stop Believing in Yourself&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always had big dreams. Everybody should. I dislike people who laugh at others for having dreams. It&amp;rsquo;s the one trait that I value more than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like my dream of becoming the top 1% of players in League of Legends, I kept on dreaming, kept on setting goals for myself, and kept on achieving them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Those who are crazy enough to think they can change the world usually do.” – Steve Jobs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember that my biggest goal as a kid was to become a billionaire. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why. It just seemed like a goal that was challenging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was far-fetched for me at the time so I broke that goal down into subgoals. When I was luckily accepted by the University of Massachusetts, Amherst, the only thing that I had on my mind was to transfer to a better university such as Columbia or the University of Michigan. The statistics told me that going to one of these schools gave me a higher probability of becoming a billionaire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my high school senior year&amp;rsquo;s second semester to accepting my admission to the University of Michigan in April 2017, everything I did was to help me transfer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quit gaming cold turkey and started studying because I had a new goal in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy, but during my first semester at UMass Amherst, I took 18 credits (18 credits is the most you can take without having to pay extra tuition) and got a 4.00 GPA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/gpa/5.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;
    title=&#34;My first semester of college&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;My first semester of college at UMass Amherst&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/gpa/6.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;
title=&#34;Last semester&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;My most recent semester at UMich&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, my goal was to get an internship at a Big 4 tech company (Facebook, Amazon, Microsoft, Google), which I achieved in September 2018 by doing LeetCode questions all summer long on top of a full-time job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During all of this, I never stopped believing in myself, and my friends and family never stopped believing in me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next goal will be to find my dream job, wherever that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In two weeks, I will be running my first marathon. In a couple years, I plan to do an Ironman and climb Mt. Everest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, I will start my own billion dollar company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: It&amp;rsquo;s also okay if your goals change. Unexpected things happen and there&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with changing your goals, as long as you don&amp;rsquo;t change them too often. To know when a goal is worth changing, I reflect and ask myself the following question, &amp;ldquo;is this goal taking me in the direction that makes me happy day-after-day or am I doing something just because other people think it&amp;rsquo;s the cool thing to do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, between my sophomore and senior year, the only thing that I wanted to do was to pursue research in machine learning (ex. get a Ph.D. in machine learning at Stanford, then work at Google DeepMind.) I went soul-searching for quite a while, but finally realized that I was only doing it because it was the hottest thing in computer science and not because I enjoyed the work. What I enjoyed was leading others and building communities and products. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/president/&#34;&gt;Being President Was The Best Thing I Did In College&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through a personal anecdote, I hope you realize the benefit of dreaming often and to never stop believing in yourself. As long as you dream and believe in yourself, you will do what is necessary to achieve your dreams. As a wise man once said,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Shoot for the moon, even if you miss, you&amp;rsquo;ll land amongst the stars.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Views: 1386&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being President Was The Best Thing I Did In College</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/president/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/president/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>

&lt;p&gt;Serving as the President of the Michigan Data Science Team (MDST) was the best thing I did in college. It was more fulfilling than any personal project, any book I&amp;rsquo;ve read, or any internship I&amp;rsquo;ve done. It also helped me hone several invaluable soft skills that would have been hard to develop in other settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-was-being-president-so-fulfilling&#34;&gt;Why Was Being President So Fulfilling?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you will see from the examples below, the things that I did and implemented created real changes in the team. They affected the productivity and happiness of people and allowed students to learn more and do more. Without me, none of this would have happened. I know this because I&amp;rsquo;ve seen the state of the team for the past 1.5 years. Even under my candidacy, my first semester was a mess. It was only when I got the exec members together at the end of the first semester to reflect and brainstorm solutions for the next semester that we were able to fix our mistakes and improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the founding of the team five years ago, the team has had problems with member retention. Though the team published papers to world-renowned conferences, few people came to meetings and few people worked on these projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;MDataHack&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my primary goals when running for president was to organize Michigan’s first technical data science hackathon (datathon). Though it was our first time organizing such an event, we were able to pull it off with great success. &lt;strong&gt;Not only did 70 students show up for the datathon, every single one of them stayed for the entire 24-hour duration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the datathon, one professor came up to us and asked us, &amp;ldquo;how many times have you organized this kind of event before?&amp;rdquo;
He was shocked when we told him that this was our first time organizing such an event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few students also came up to me to thank me during and after the datathon about how great of an event it was. One student told me about how long he’s waited for a data science hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a member who&amp;rsquo;s been on the team since its foundation, this was the most successful thing that the organization has ever done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/president/1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;High school junior year transcript&#34;
title=&#34;I wasn&#39;t kidding.&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;A team of Chemistry Ph.D. students presenting to a professor&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/president/2.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;High school junior year transcript&#34;
title=&#34;I wasn&#39;t kidding.&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;Excited winners&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Work Sessions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of my first semester as president, we realized that there were things that definitely needed improvement. I remember we had only one member show up to our project meeting during exam week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address some of these issues, for our last exec meeting, I asked everybody to reflect on our current state and brainstorm solutions to our problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result of reflecting on our problems at the end of my presidency’s first semester, we implemented work sessions. We wanted to create a more collaborative environment for students and to make the MDST function more like a team than a research group. We wanted people to work together and get to know each other as this would make their time with the team more enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Restructuring&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my first semester, we tried a flat organizational hierarchy. This meant that we had one project team and that there were no fixed leaders. Instead, we had people assign tasks on GitHub and people did them at will. This resulted in a total of 18 people contributing to the project during the semester, but only one person was doing all the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by The Mythical Man-Month and realizing that an 18-person team wasn’t very effective, I suggested that we create smaller teams of 4-5. We also decided to scope out project leaders for the project teams. By giving people leadership positions early on, we could groom them into taking over positions on the exec board as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating this sort of 3-level hierarchy also helped to make the team more enjoyable for members as they developed stronger relationships with their teammates. Having project leads also meant that we could work on more projects in a semester. This allowed more students to work on a project of their desire, further increasing engagement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As a result of #2 and #3, we had 30 people showed up to the election day meeting, with about 15 people running for the 6 positions.&lt;/strong&gt; We had speech after speech from candidates from departments as diverse as Ph.D. candidates in Evolutionary Biology and Ecology to Ph.D. candidates in Mechanical Engineering. &lt;strong&gt;When I was running the year prior, only 3 people showed up to the election day meeting. Not a single person showed up to watch.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, all these things that we did above seem obvious and don&amp;rsquo;t seem hard to implement. The hard part was realizing what went wrong and finding the right solutions. &lt;strong&gt;That it was the hardest thing that I’ve done in college which made it all the more rewarding when we achieved success. I was in the dark trying to find my way the entire time.&lt;/strong&gt; During most of the first semester, I was still seeking guidance from the previous president. By the end of the first semester, I was taking the reins and implementing new ideas and trying new things. Like a startup, I realized that there wasn’t some straightforward path to success. I had to make different hypotheses and run experiments to see what worked and what doesn’t. Second, to actually attempting to starting a company, being the president of an org is one of the best ways to learn some of the skills for becoming a founder. Especially since the cost of failure is so much lower than actually starting a company which may cost years of your career or school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It felt so good to make such an improvement. To see students collaborating and having fun when they weren&amp;rsquo;t before. To see students continue coming to meetings even during exam week and the very last meeting. It&amp;rsquo;s a feeling that is addicting and is the most rewarding thing that I have ever done in college. It gave me purpose and a sense of accomplishment. &lt;strong&gt;The accomplishment of leading a group to success has been more rewarding to me than any personal achievement ever. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t getting the highest test score in some class, I created a sense of community and improved the lives of others.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-did-i-learn&#34;&gt;What Did I Learn?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To become the best leader I could, I tried to improve my leadership skills. These are a few of the things that I learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;delegation&#34;&gt;Delegation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first began my presidency, I had a hard time delegating. &lt;strong&gt;I wanted to do the work myself not because I didn’t think other people couldn’t do a good job, but because as a workaholic, I gained personal satisfaction from getting work done.&lt;/strong&gt; Delegating to me was not doing work, it was getting other people to do it for me. Over the course of my presidency, I learned to delegate. I realized that delegating allows me to work on the tasks that I’m more suited to work on and allows the entire exec team to get more work done. Once I started to change my mindset from &lt;strong&gt;“what can I do for the team” to “how can I get the team to do more” was a big inflection point for me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;public-speaking&#34;&gt;Public Speaking&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve seldom had difficulties to inspire a single person. As the size of an audience increases, it becomes more difficult to understand your audience and adjust your delivery and content. During the past year, I lead exec meetings of four undergrads and one Ph.D. student, lead project meetings of 20-30 people of diverse academic backgrounds, spoke to over 70 students and professors and presented at a mass meeting of over 250 students. Though I still have much to improve in this area, I enjoyed taking this responsibility and I’m much better at reading the audience now than ever before. One day, I’d like to be so good that I can energize an audience or get everybody tearing up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;future&#34;&gt;Future&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I could continue serving as the president of the team forever. There are tons of changes that I want to put in place to make the team even better. But, I am graduating this next semester so I must move on. I will serve as an advisor of the team from now on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, I want to thank the rest of the executive board for their hard work and hours put in on weekends and during exam weeks. Without them, none of these achievements would have been possible. Wish you all the best in your future endeavors and I hope that you’ve enjoyed working with me as I have with you all.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Land Your Dream Internship</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/internship/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/internship/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>

&lt;p&gt;Here are five pieces of wisdom that I&amp;rsquo;ve gained from applying to hundreds of companies and speaking to hundreds of recruiters in the past four years. These tips aren&amp;rsquo;t just valuable for landing internship offers from the Big 4 (Facebook, Amazon, Microsoft, Google), but also at other companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-your-online-presence-matters-more-than-you-think&#34;&gt;1. Your Online Presence Matters More Than You Think&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people think that maintaining a personal website or LinkedIn is a waste of time. I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered two misconceptions. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recruiters don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to look at your personal website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I applied to Google&amp;rsquo;s software engineering internship when I was a sophomore at UMass Amherst. According to many applicants, the online application for sophomores is a &amp;ldquo;black hole&amp;rdquo;. You apply and never hear back from them again. You can imagine how ecstatic I was when I received an email from my recruiter that I had landed two phone interviews with Google software engineers. &lt;em&gt;How did I not get sucked into the &amp;ldquo;black hole?&lt;/em&gt; I believe it was because of &lt;a href=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/ac_hack/&#34;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt;. By looking at the Google Analytics for my website, I discovered that a person from Mountain View, CA (where Google&amp;rsquo;s HQ is located) had visited my site between the time I submitted my application and the time my recruiter contacted me. My website was kept quite private at the time so it was unlikely that a random person from Mountain View just happened to stumble upon my website. Because of this, I believe that the reason I was one of the only sophomores at UMass Amherst to be interviewed by Google was because of my blog post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recruiters don&amp;rsquo;t offer interviews through LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two weeks into my junior year at UMich, I recieved a LinkedIn message from a Microsoft recruiter informing me that I was a great fit for their company. She said that I could begin their recruiting process by forwarding her my resume. This was eye-opening for me as I&amp;rsquo;ve never heard of recruiters actually reaching out through LinkedIn. In fact, I didn&amp;rsquo;t email her back for at least a week because I was so sure that things like this didn&amp;rsquo;t happen and that this was some sort of scam. Now, I&amp;rsquo;m glad to say that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t and I was scheduled for an on-campus interview shortly after without having to submit any online application or talk to any recruiter at a career fair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/internship/linkedin.png&#34; alt=&#34;LinkedIn message from Microsoft recruiter&#34;
    title=&#34;LinkedIn message&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The takeaway here is that your online presence matters. Some recruiters do look at your personal website and LinkedIn profile. So, if you want the best chance at getting interviews, post about your projects and keep your LinkedIn profile up to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-it-s-a-numbers-game&#34;&gt;2. It&amp;rsquo;s a Numbers Game&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re a freshman or sophomore, apply to as many internships as you possibly can. The more, the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I submitted applications to 200 companies during my sophomore year.&lt;/strong&gt; Guess how many I heard back from? 15. How many offers did I end up getting? 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many sophomores in college, getting an internship isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. Thus, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to understand why you should be applying to as many companies as you can. Instead of trying to get into your dream company, you should be trying to get into any company at all. See tip #5 for more on this. Use aggregate resources such as &lt;a href=&#34;intern.supply&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;intern.supply&lt;/a&gt; to simplify the process. Set a schedule for yourself. It takes a few minutes to submit an application. Spend 30 minutes a day before bed or in the morning after you wake up to submit a few applications. At an ample rate of five minutes per application (6 applications/day), you&amp;rsquo;ll have submitted about 170 applications in a a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expect rejection.&lt;/strong&gt; Instead of being dissapointed when you don&amp;rsquo;t hear back from a company after applying online, think of it as the norm. The important thing is to get back up and keep trying. Don&amp;rsquo;t get discouraged!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my junior year, I interviewed with and was rejected by some of my dream companies, Google, Facebook, and Apple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again during my senior year, I was rejected by Google, Facebook, Apple, Tesla, and Airbnb. Even as a senior from UMich, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even get an interview with RobinHood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep calm and apply on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-recruiting-processes-aren-t-perfect&#34;&gt;3. Recruiting Processes Aren&amp;rsquo;t Perfect&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing is. Instead of complaining of how recruiters take forever to respond, be proactive and reach out to them continuously. Go meet them at campus events or career fairs. Ping them on LinkedIn. Do whatever you can to get in touch with them. &lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s up to you, not them, to move you forward in the process.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to tip #3, never give up once you get started in a recruiting process with a company. Even if it means emailing the recruiter again and again, week after week. Keep emailing them until they reply or move on to the next stage in your process. Sometimes it may even be beneficial to talk to the recruiter in person at a career fair if they don&amp;rsquo;t seem to be replying to your emails. Of course, give them at least a week before reminding them. And do it politely. They&amp;rsquo;re not required to to do anything for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was interviewing with Fidelity Investments, my recruiter changed and after emailing the new recruiter it seemed like I never got a reply. Thus, I went to the campus career fair to find the recruiter in person. I talked to him, handed him my resume, and then got my resume forwarded to the managers at their headquarters. Without doing this, I would&amp;rsquo;ve been jobless during my sophomore summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-study&#34;&gt;4. Study&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Study for your interviews!  This tip is underrated for many freshman and sophomores. Many freshmen and sophomores don&amp;rsquo;t expect to get interviews, so when they do, they can be unprepared. I learned this the hard way when I got my Google interview during my sophomore year. Those were probably two of the most stressful weeks of my life. Learn from my mistake and start preparing for your interviews earlier. Note: cramming does not work for programming interviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to land your dream internship, start preparing for the interview the summer before the fall recruiting season. By September, you should know your data structures and algorithms like the back of your hand. The steps that you need to take to land your dream internship are quite straightforward. &lt;strong&gt;Though it may vary from person to person, generally speaking if you do about 100 LeetCode medium questions you can get into any of the Big 4.&lt;/strong&gt; If you want to get into uber-cometitive companies such as Airbnb, you may need to do 150 LeetCode medium questions. I think I did about 50 medium, 50 easy, and a few hard LeetCode questions before getting a full-time offer from Microsoft. Knowing what to do is easy. Just schedule two hours on your calendar each day to do two questions on &lt;a href=&#34;www.leetcode.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LeetCode&lt;/a&gt;. When I was doing interview prep during my junior year, I did two questions after dinner each day. If you can keep this up for the entire summer, your chances of getting into your dream internship will be quite good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easy part is knowing what the process entails. The hard part is developing the motivation to follow through with your plan. I helped motivate myself by inviting friends to do interview prep with me. When one friend was busy, I invited another friend. This way I always had somebody to keep myself accountable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/internship/schedule.png&#34; alt=&#34;LeetCode schedule&#34;
    title=&#34;LeetCode schedule&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-beggars-can-t-be-choosers&#34;&gt;5. Beggars Can&amp;rsquo;t Be Choosers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tip is for those who are having a hard time (especially freshmen and sophomores) finding internships. You have to take what you can get, even if it means making sacrifices such as seeing friends and family or going on vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks before the end of my freshmen year, one of my professors sent out an email looking to hire a summer intern. Long story short, I got the job because I was flexible with where I was going to live, and the work schedule. I started as soon as school ended and moved into a spare room in the professors home. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/independence/&#34;&gt;Independence&lt;/a&gt; for why I think the professor chose me over other candidates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Share your own tips below!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/22/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I turned 22. You could say I had a mini quarter-life crisis. Most people retire at about age 60. That would put me at a third of the way through my career. It&amp;rsquo;s also not news that most people lay the foundations of their career in their 20s and early 30s, leading to an average peak in salary in their 40s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Meg Jay, Ph.D., author of the Defining Decade says,
&amp;ldquo;Eighty percent of life&amp;rsquo;s most defining moments take place by age thirty-five. Two-thirds of lifetime wage growth happens in the first ten years of a career.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This led me to think about what I am currently doing with my life and what I want to do with my 20s. How do I want to live my 20s? How do I want to live my life to minimize regret? I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be in my 30s and have nothing to show for my 20s. Especially since I only have one life. I should use my time as wisely as I can. As depressing as it sounds, I&amp;rsquo;m only going to get to live through my 20s once. And I&amp;rsquo;m already a fifth of my way through them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What changes can I make to my current way of living to minimize future regret? I came up with the following changes to make the best use of my time on Earth by using the following thought framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If I turned 30 today, what activities would I regret doing the most in my 20s?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wasting time on Reddit. As I did with gaming, Snapchat, and Instagram, it&amp;rsquo;s time that I go cold-turkey on Reddit and stop using Reddit once and for all. If there was one thing that I would regret doing in my 20s, it would be wasting my time on Reddit. LeechBlock NG, a Firefox add-on and privacy restrictions on my iPhone will help me get through the first few weeks of not using Reddit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like 1., stop wasting time on LinkedIn. LinkedIn is the new Facebook for many people including myself. Though I only spend a few minutes on it each day, those minutes add up. I&amp;rsquo;d much rather be working on something tangible than caring about what other people are up to. No successful person achieves success by updating their LinkedIn profile or scrolling through their news feed. They achieve success by working hard at whatever they are working on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take risks. When I&amp;rsquo;m in my 30s and 40s, I may be married and have kids. I won&amp;rsquo;t have the time to take large career risks such as starting a company or joining an early-stage startup. If I don&amp;rsquo;t try to start my own company in my 20s, I know it will be the biggest regret of my life. I am full of energy, time, and vigor right now. I should take advantage of it. From now on, I will be taking more career risks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s often easier to take risks early in your career; you don’t have much to lose, and you potentially have a lot to gain. Once you’ve gotten yourself to a point where you have your basic obligations covered you should try to make it easy to take risks. Look for small bets you can make where you lose 1x if you’re wrong but make 100x if it works. Then make a bigger bet in that direction. - &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.samaltman.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sam Altman, chairman of YCombinator and co-chairman of OpenAI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, happy birthday to you too, Sam!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is one thing that I gained from reflecting on my current state, it is to live each moment with purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Information is Not Always Good</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2018/information/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2018/information/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, I was debating with my co-workers Alice and Bob about whether or not having more information is always benefical to a person. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to be able to express their thoughts with high fidelity, so I will only express mine here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having more information does not allow us to make better decisions. In fact, a lot of the time, we can benefit from having less information. A few examples that we discussed included the infamous story of George Dantzig (shown in the intro of Good Will Hunting), who walked into class late one day believing that the two questions he saw on the board were homework questions. Only later did he discover that the two questions he solved for homework were famous unsolved statistics questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If he hadn&amp;rsquo;t walked into the classroom late that day and heard that it was a famous unsolved question, he wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have even attempted solving the question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another example that came up just the other day was when I was working on updating a software program at my internship. My mentor told me that I would have to complete overhauling a machine learning model before the upgrade could be completed because of incompatible dependencies. Because of my mentor&amp;rsquo;s authority and perceived knowledge, I didn&amp;rsquo;t give what he said any second thought and just accepted it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Bob wasn&amp;rsquo;t told this and because he wanted to use some features of 1.8 pretty badly, he tried to upgrade it to 1.8 anyway. In this way, without the information given to him from a person in a position of higher power first, he never gave a second thought about trying to upgrade it himself. Lo and behold, we didn&amp;rsquo;t actually need to touch the machine learning model before the upgrade and the request was merged late last night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, statistics such as how unlikely it is for you to start a company and bring it to IPO can only prevent people from succeeding. The best way to go about this is to have an optimistic you-can-do-it attitude and try your best to ignore the pessimistic facts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes:
This isn&amp;rsquo;t really about making better decisions, it&amp;rsquo;s more like bringing up a point that it&amp;rsquo;s not always a good thing when you get told to do something because that may make you limit abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a Better Software Engineer</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2018/swe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2018/swe/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently realized that the skills you learn as a software engineer (SWE) are disjoint from the skills that you learn in school. Below are some of my findings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-nobody-knows-the-answer-but-it-s-out-there-somewhere&#34;&gt;1. Nobody knows the answer, but it&amp;rsquo;s out there somewhere.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s up to you and only you to figure it out. That&amp;rsquo;s what the company is paying you to do. Problem-solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When my internship first started, I shot questions at my mentor, full-timers, and other interns what seemed like every hour. After a while, I realized that they didn&amp;rsquo;t know the answers to my questions either. Either we would figure it out on the spot together or they would try to give me the most guidance they could (usually not much). Then, I had to figure out the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a dichotomy here. In school, you are able to ask your professor anything about the class and get a straightforward answer. But, in the workplace, there&amp;rsquo;s no such thing. This is because when you work, you are doing research. You&amp;rsquo;re doing more than regurgitating facts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-take-it-slow-but-not-too-slow&#34;&gt;2. Take it slow, but not too slow.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning takes time, debugging takes time, and detours are normal. It&amp;rsquo;s a primary SWE skill to be able to determine how long the detour should be. As interns, we tend to try and decrease this detour as much as possible to get as much done as possible, but as I&amp;rsquo;ve recently learned, that isn&amp;rsquo;t the most optimal plan. Instead, you should try to increase your time on detours to provide a more solid foundation for later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I mean by a detour is the path in which you take to solve a problem such as an error or bug. It usually requires a lot of googling, time on Stack Overflow, reading through the documentation, amongst other things. Spend more time actually learning why something works instead of copying and pasting code. At first, you will seem to make slower progress, but you will soon realize that you&amp;rsquo;ve actually created a better foundation for yourself that will benefit you in the long-run. It&amp;rsquo;s more or less about investing your time in the right place now for long-term benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example, instead of copying a Linux command from some website and running it, I now take apart each command and flag and learn what each one does. This means that in the future, I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to use those commands in my own way instead of having to search online again and again for the similar commands or flags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.ycombinator.com/learning-math-for-machine-learning/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;In fact, investing in peer-driven learning environments can make your long-term work more effective, despite short-term costs in time&amp;rdquo;,&lt;/a&gt; says Vincent Chen, a student at Stanford University.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super Linux Warp Pipe</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2018/pipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2018/pipe/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Today at work I came across a problem that I managed to solve using multiple Linux pipes. What I needed to do to solve the problem was count the frequency of words existing between a certain context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a simplified version of what the input looked like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Where is the { FRUIT apple } ?
Is the { PLANT tree } within the ground ?
The { FRUIT banana } ate some { FRUIT banana } .
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I wanted to look for the frequency of words only with the &lt;code&gt;FRUIT&lt;/code&gt; label, then the intended output should look like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;2 banana
1 apple
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To prevent a breach of confidentiality, I have replaced the actual words with something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The command that ended up doing the trick was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cat input_file | grep -o -P &#39;(?&amp;lt;={ FRUIT).*?(?= })&#39; | grep -v &amp;quot;^\s$&amp;quot; | sort | uniq -c | sort -bnr &amp;gt; output_file
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below, I will break down what each part does. I will cover the following commands and flags: &lt;code&gt;grep -o -P -v&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;sort -bnr&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;uniq -c&lt;/code&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll cover regular expressions (regex) in another post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;grep -o&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;grep --only-matching&lt;/code&gt; basically matches and prints out only the matched phrase. For example, since I wanted to count the number of occurrences of each of these words or phrases, I wanted to not only search for the words between &lt;code&gt;{ FRUIT&lt;/code&gt;  and &lt;code&gt;}&lt;/code&gt;, but print them out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;grep -P&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;grep --perl-regexp&lt;/code&gt; is pretty self-explanatory. It allows you to specify a Perl regex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;grep -v&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;grep --inverse-match&lt;/code&gt; selects lines that don&amp;rsquo;t match the regex. It&amp;rsquo;s the negation of standard grep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;uniq -c&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;uniq --count&lt;/code&gt; prefixes each line with the number of occurrences of each phrase or word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sort -b&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;sort --ignore-leading-blanks&lt;/code&gt; ignores leading blanks. Surprising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sort -n&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;sort --numeric-sort&lt;/code&gt; sorts in ascending numerical order. (0, 1, 2, &amp;hellip; 9)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sort -r&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;sort --reverse&lt;/code&gt; reverses the sort.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another New Site?</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2018/another-new-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2018/another-new-site/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;So, it seems like every few months I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling discontent with my personal website, thus prompting me to rehaul my website over and over again. This frequent rehauling can be boiled down to two reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have never really felt satisfied with the overall design and aesthetic of my personal website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t made up my mind about starting my blog back up again or not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been toying around with Jekyll and Bootstrap recently, and then I found Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo is a static site generator that uses Go for templating which means that you can easily separate your content and the code that builds the site. It&amp;rsquo;s completely open-source and was actually based on Jekyll. &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16472395&amp;amp;ref=codebldr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Many other people agree with me on the awesomeness of Hugo.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever wanted to create your own site that&amp;rsquo;s easy to maintain and free to host, check out my next post for a great tutorial that&amp;rsquo;s written for the average person in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: Since creating this website, I&amp;rsquo;m really enjoying writing again. I think the medium in which you post on is really important. For me, at least.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosting Hugo Using GitHub</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2018/a-better-hugo-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2018/a-better-hugo-tutorial/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;In this short tutorial, you will be creating two repositories, one that will store your Hugo source files, and one that will store the files neccessary to view your website. The website repo is called &lt;code&gt;public&lt;/code&gt; and will be inside of your source repository. This will be done by using a &lt;code&gt;git submodule&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guide requires you to have git installed, a Hugo website that you can easily clone from it&amp;rsquo;s github repo, and a GitHub account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a GitHub repository for your website. Name it &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;USERNAME&amp;gt;.github.io&lt;/code&gt;. All your files neccessary for your website will be stored here.
Ex: wesleytian.github.io&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a Github repository for all of your Hugo source code. Name it anything you like &lt;em&gt;except&lt;/em&gt; for &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;USERNAME&amp;gt;.github.io&lt;/code&gt;.
Ex: blog&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Navigate to a directory where you want your source files to be stored. &lt;code&gt;cd &amp;lt;DIRECTORY&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;git clone &amp;lt;SOURCE_REPO_URL&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;
Ex: &lt;code&gt;cd webdev&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/wesleytian/blog.git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Change directory to the repository you just cloned. &lt;code&gt;cd &amp;lt;SOURCE&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;
Ex: &lt;code&gt;cd blog&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git submodule add -b master &amp;lt;WEBSITE_REPO_URL&amp;gt; public&lt;/code&gt;
Ex: &lt;code&gt;git submodule add -b master https://github.com/wesleytian/wesleytian.github.io.git public&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Copy all of your Hugo source files into the source folder except the public folder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a script based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/hosting-and-deployment/hosting-on-github/#put-it-into-a-script&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://gohugo.io/hosting-and-deployment/hosting-on-github/#put-it-into-a-script&lt;/a&gt;
and run &lt;code&gt;./deploy.sh &amp;quot;Optional commit message&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;. Do both of these steps in your source folder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You are now done! You should now be able to access your website through &lt;a href=&#34;https://USERNAME.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://USERNAME.github.io/&lt;/a&gt; It make take a few minutes for your DNS to refresh.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that your website is now up to date in the &lt;USERNAME&gt;.github.io repo, but your source files have not yet been added, committed, and pushed to GitHub. To do so, simply type &lt;code&gt;git add . &amp;amp;&amp;amp; git commit -m &amp;quot;commit message&amp;quot; &amp;amp;&amp;amp; git push origin master&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: This guide is based off of &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/hosting-and-deployment/hosting-on-github/#step-by-step-instructions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://gohugo.io/hosting-and-deployment/hosting-on-github/#step-by-step-instructions&lt;/a&gt;
but is more detailed, and includes steps that were missing from the original documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: You also have to clone a theme into the themes/ folder or else you will get a &amp;ldquo;missing layouts&amp;rdquo; error.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking an Inadequate Air Conditioner – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2017/ac_hack_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2017/ac_hack_2/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/ac_hack/&#34;&gt;Click here for part 1.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my professor and I created the prototype for the Remote Thermostat in, we worked on the printed circuit board layout using EAGLE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we placed the order through a Chinese website and then waited for the board to be delivered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/ac_hack_2/IMG_5913.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;pic&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opensprinkler.com/introducing-opensprinkler-bee-2-0-a-wifi-enabled-universal-sprinkler-controller/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://opensprinkler.com/introducing-opensprinkler-bee-2-0-a-wifi-enabled-universal-sprinkler-controller/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>College Advice</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/advice/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-take-classes-with-the-course-chair&#34;&gt;1. Take classes with the course chair&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking classes with the course chair for courses with many sections such as Linear Algebra guarantees you a proficient teacher.  They will most likely provide extra perks such as review sessions and review sheets. You are also guaranteed that the instructor will cover everything on the tests so you won&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about your professor omitting something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took Calculus I with the course chair during my freshman year. On the first day of class, he shared with the class a special link that included all the practice exams and their solutions since the creation of the course. Additionally, he told us that the link was exclusive to our class and insisted that we didn&amp;rsquo;t share the login info with other sections of the course. I suppose that it may be related to keeping his position as the course chair but I that&amp;rsquo;s speculation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if the course chair&amp;rsquo;s section is full, you can always e-mail them or talk to them in person to reserve a seat. Remember to be polite as they aren&amp;rsquo;t required by any means to fulfill your request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-always-sit-in-the-front&#34;&gt;2. Always sit in the front&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sitting at the front of the class makes you less afraid to shout out answers and ask questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The instructor is more likely to call on you and answer your question. The instructor will notice you more and if you provide a continuous stream of answers and engaging questions, then you are sure to obtain a special seat in the eyes of the instructor. e.g. they will be more likely to help you out when you need help for exams or when asking about research opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be easier for you you to pay attention because there is nothing in front of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-don-t-pick-general-education-courses-for-the-easy-a&#34;&gt;3. Don&amp;rsquo;t pick General Education courses for the easy A&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, think about what you can learn from it.
Then, think about what the department&amp;rsquo;s reputation at your university is, the background of the instructor teaching it.
Then finally consider the course&amp;rsquo;s perceived difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fulfilling your general education requirements by taking the easiest classes at your university wastes both your money (or your parents!) and your time. Don&amp;rsquo;t select courses only because you heard they are easy! Although, you may benefit the most if you can find a course that benefits you in the long-run or plainly interests you AND it&amp;rsquo;s easy, then that&amp;rsquo;s fine. Don&amp;rsquo;t rank the difficulty of the class over everything else. What I mean about benefiting you in the long-run are courses such as taking Game Theory as a Computer Science major. Though it may seem irrelevant, it is applicable in AI, business, mathematics, psychology, and other fields. Not only did Game Theory interest me, but it may actually benefit me in the long-run!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, you should do research about the instructor and department of the general education classes you want to take. The University of Massachusetts, Amherst, is world-renowned for their work in Artificial Intelligence (AI), especially in Reinforcement Learning, a subdomain of AI. but what UMass Amherst truly excels at is its Linguistics department in the College of Humanities and Fine Arts.  PhDs.org ranks UMass between rank 4 and 8 in the United States and so fulfilling a general education requirement by taking a linguistics intro course is sure to be interesting and taught extremely well. Where else can you learn from the smartest professors in their field?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phds.org/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;PhDs.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;phds.org&lt;/a&gt; for the departments that your university excels at. Undergraduates seldom discuss the quality of graduate departments, but if you talk to graduate students or professors they will know for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to take your interests into account. UMass Amherst ranks 1st/2nd out of 32 programs for Food Science, 1st–7th out of 41 programs for Kinesiology, and 3rd–11th out of 83 programs for Polymer Science and Engineering. But, if you&amp;rsquo;re not interested in food science, kinesiology, or polymer science, then don&amp;rsquo;t take it! You will never know what great professors you will meet and things you will learn from fulfilling a general education requirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve taken full advantage of this tip since I&amp;rsquo;ve transferred to the University of Michigan. I&amp;rsquo;m now taking Philosophy classes here as UMich ranks top three in the world for their doctoral philosophy program.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking an Inadequate Air Conditioner – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/ac_hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/ac_hack/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;It was scorching hot this summer in Amherst, Massachusetts. Especially because my room was on the second floor, the room temperature would often rise to over 100° F during midday. The house I stayed in didn&amp;rsquo;t have a central HVAC (heat-ventilation-air-conditioning) system built into the house so we opted for a window AC that could be inserted into the frame of the window and be plugged into the wall outlet for power. The problem with this AC was that not only did it not have a specific temperature setting, but also that once turned on, you could not turn it off with having to manually turn the dial on the AC. During the day this was not a problem as I could just turn around from my desk and turn the dial. At night, however, there was a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one enjoys waking up in the middle of the night. What is less enjoyable is being woken up in the middle of the night from the sweating from the heat or shivering from the cold. Suddenly, I realized that a simple solution would be to create a device that could not only sense the temperature but also automate the turning on and off of the air conditioner. Since the air conditioner was plugged into the wall outlet, all I had to do was find a way to control that switch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turns out Etekcity, as well as a handful of other sellers on Amazon, sell a product called a remote outlet switch. &lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/ac_hack/outlet.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Outlet&#34; /&gt; This product includes a remote with on and off buttons and a few of the remote outlet switches. The remote&amp;rsquo;s function is being able to control the current that runs through the outlet switch by either closing the current or releasing it. This was the exact thing I needed to make this hack work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I had to design the device. The device would need to be able to sense the temperature, allow the user to set the temperature, and mimic the remote&amp;rsquo;s signal to control the remote outlet switch. Using Arduino libraries and hardware and a DHT II sensor I was able to create my first prototype. Additionally, it included a WiFi chip, a 433MhZ transmitter, and receiver, and an LCD screen that could display the current temperature, humidity, set temperature etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/ac_hack/prototype.png&#34; alt=&#34;Prototype&#34; /&gt;
And to add the programmable part, I used Blynk to add certain widgets that connect to the device through WiFi. &lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/ac_hack/blynk.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt; I am now able to see my current room temperature from anywhere using my phone and control the temperature from anywhere as well. The Blynk app additionally includes a graph that shows the change of my room temperature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, I am working on my own application that will support this device. Using it, you will be able to set different time intervals and control a myriad of other settings such as short cycle duration, being able to use the heat index instead of temperature, and the hysteresis range. If you work from 9-5 Mon-Fri, then you will be able to set a specific temperature or turn off your AC for those times. The app allows you set an infinite number of intervals making it superior to its competitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/ac_hack/ionic.png&#34; alt=&#34;Ionic&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/ac_hack/IMG_2621.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Ionic 2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very useful device for managing your room/house temperature and can even extend to an unlimited range of uses. It can be used to control a humidifier, fans, heaters, or other types of temperature regulating appliances that can be powered by a wall outlet. This device can save your electricity bills, protect foods from perishing, keep rooms from becoming moldy, or just making sure that you get a good night&amp;rsquo;s rest. After all, one-third of our lives is spent sleeping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike current products that share a similar function with this gadget, my device is separate from the outlet. This is crucial to providing an accurate recording of the room temperature. Many thermostats, even the more advanced ones sense the temperature close to the area where the AC is placed. Therefore, the temperature sensed will always be lower and different from the actual room temperature that you feel. Having the switch and the device separate solves this problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AC:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/ac_hack/ac.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;AC&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks after I created this, Rui found a few other similar gadgets that people made to try and regulate their room temperature. One of them decided to use a breadboard and flimsy wires to control the surge. (Very dangerous!) &lt;a href=&#34;http://hackaday.com/2016/08/05/arduino-replaces-bad-ac-thermostat-hacker-stays-cool/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Arduino Replaces Bad AC Thermostat, Hacker Stays Cool&lt;/a&gt; which also bears resemblance to this &lt;a href=&#34;http://hackaday.com/2015/06/11/arduino-controlled-air-conditioner&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Arduino Controlled Air Conditioner&lt;/a&gt;. Both of which requires the person to set the desired temperature by walking up to the AC and turning a knob. I also would not recommend tampering with the AC itself because 120v can kill you! All in all, I think that the best solutions to some things require a well-balanced incorporation of both hardware and software. Stay tuned for newer versions of the WiFi Remote Outlet Thermostat!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Happiest Moment of My Life</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/olympus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/olympus/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/olympus/IMG_3114.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Sunrise from Refuge A&#34;
    title=&#34;Sunrise from Refuge A&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;Sunrise from Refuge A&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always like to plan things out before I do them. Especially with hiking mountains in a country of which language I did not know, it was especially crucial for me to plan things out before hand. I searched online and found close to nothing that would help me prepare for Mt. Olympus. I basically went to Greece with no knowledge of Mt. Olympus so I had to figure everything out on the way. So, hopefully, this blog post will help guide those who wish to hike one of the most beautiful mountains on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;table-of-contents&#34;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#getting_there&#34;&gt;Getting There&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#preparation&#34;&gt;Preparation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#routes&#34;&gt;Routes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#faq&#34;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#pictures&#34;&gt;Pictures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#final_verdict&#34;&gt;Final Verdict&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Location: Litochoro, Greece&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![](http://www.english-online.at/history/ancient-greece/location-of-mount-olympus.gif)
 --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;getting_there&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-there&#34;&gt;Getting There&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you arrive in Greece, it is very common to arrive at the ATH (Athens International Airport). There is a train at St. Larissa* (different from the city named Larissa) St. Larissa is a metro stop on the Red Line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/olympus/IMG_3110.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Metro&#34;
    title=&#34;Metro&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;Metro&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take the train from St. Larissa (Athens) to Larissa (4 hours)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.wesleytian.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/&#34; alt=&#34;Train at Athens&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Transfer trains at the train station Larissa to go to Litochoro (1 major stop) (30 minutes)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the Litochoro train station to the village it takes 5-10 minutes by taxi. (6km)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can look for the train schedule at www.trainose.gr The trains are rarely full so you can just buy the tickets at the station.
The train will stop a couple of times before reaching a major stop. Listen to &amp;ldquo;Litochoro&amp;rdquo; (Lih-toe-hoe-roe)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;prepration&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparation&#34;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/olympus/IMG_3007.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Packing List&#34;
    title=&#34;Packing List&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;Packing List&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Sun protection] Sun hat, Sunglasses, Sunscreen&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Cold protection] Baselayer (long-sleeve recommended), Midlayer (fleece, or softshell jacket) It can get to 5C&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Wind protection] Pants, windbreaker&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Food] Snacks with proteins, fats, and carbs, 500-1000 calories (bring more food if you want to spend less money and vice versa)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Water] 1.5L&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Other] Hiking map with trails, compass, camera, first aid kit&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Overnight stay] Toiletries, plastic bag for trash, charger, phone charger, money&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: DO NOT bring only nuts. I basically ate none of it then relied on the food at the refuge. Eating only nuts SUCKS! Bars and bread are much better.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overnight stay costs 13 euros and the a full meal costs around 10. Also bring money for the taxis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;routes&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;routes&#34;&gt;Routes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Most Common Route&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Terms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Litochoro - the Small town with a population of 7000 in northern Greece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wesleytian.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/IMG_2992.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wesleytian.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/IMG_2992.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Small Town of Litochoro
Mt. Olympus - Tallest mountain in Greece, it is a series of multiple peaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wesleytian.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/IMG_3177.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wesleytian.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/IMG_3177.jpg&lt;/a&gt; Prionia&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prionia - (1100m) The last place where vehicles can drive to. It has a restaurant, bathroom and water fountains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wesleytian.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/IMG_3070.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wesleytian.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/IMG_3070.jpg&lt;/a&gt; Refuge A&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refuge A (2100 m). - One of the Refuges on the mountain. There are multiple Refuges on the mountain, but it is the only Refuge on the way if you take the Prionia route. Refuge A offers a place to sleep for over 90 people a night and warm food and water. They also have a bountiful supply of snacks and other goods such as socks that you can buy. You can charge your phone there as well.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hikenow.net/images/Greece/MtOlympus/img/IMG_3430.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.hikenow.net/images/Greece/MtOlympus/img/IMG_3430.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
Skala -  It leads to either Skolio or Mytikas (2866m)
Skolio - The Second highest peak. (2911 m)
Mytikas - The highest peak. (2918 m) Requires YDS class 3 scrambling&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/b/b2/Mytikas_from_Skala.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/b/b2/Mytikas_from_Skala.jpg&lt;/a&gt; Mytikas from Skala&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the most experienced hikers will follow this approach to hiking Mt. Olympus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;day-1&#34;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(You can start the Day 1 Hike anytime you want. I recommend starting it in the morning so it is not as hot and you have more time to adjust to the elevation. More info in the Tips section below.)
@ T 0-  Take a taxi to Prionia
@30 min -Begin hike from Prionia towards Refuge A. Follow the E4 trail (basically the only visible trail) and the clear directions towards the Refuge.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wesleytian.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/IMG_3034.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wesleytian.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/IMG_3034.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
@3hours 30min - Arrive at Refuge A (2100m)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total hiking time: 3 hours&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/olympus/IMG_3105.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Dinner (Spaghetti Bolognese with Orange Soda&#34;
    title=&#34;Dinner (Spaghetti Bolognese with Orange Soda&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;Dinner (Spaghetti Bolognese with Orange Soda&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay at Refuge A for the night&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;day-2&#34;&gt;Day 2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:00 Breakfast opens. Eat breakfast.
7:00 Sun rises, set out for the hike. Follow the E4 trail towards Skala (Ascent)
(2.25 hours)
9:30 Arrive at Skala. Take path to Mytikas (Requires Class 3 Scrambling)
(45 minutes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/olympus/P1220774.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Sunrise from Refuge A&#34;
    title=&#34;Sunrise from Refuge A&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; ** &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/olympus/P1220770.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Sunrise from Refuge A&#34;
    title=&#34;Sunrise from Refuge A&#34; class=&#34;center_norm_rounded&#34;/&gt;
&lt;center&gt; ** &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10:30 Reach Mytikas (15 minutes)&lt;br&gt;
10:45 Start climbing down to Refuge A (Descent) (3 hours)&lt;br&gt;
13:30 Reach Refuge A. Rest. (1 hour)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14:30 Refuge A &amp;ndash;Prionia (Descent) (3 hours)&lt;br&gt;
17:30 Arrive at Prionia. Take Taxi* back to Litochoro (30 minutes)&lt;br&gt;
18:00 Arrive back at Litochoro.&lt;br&gt;
Total hiking time: 9 hours&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no readily available taxis so you can either call one at the restaurant or preschedule one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;faq&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;faq&#34;&gt;FAQ&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can I summit Mytikas and come back down in one day?&lt;/strong&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m sure there will be many of you out there who are asking the question. Can I hike Mt. Olympus in one day? I also wondered that and I had attempted to do it. When I got to Prionia that morning, it was raining very hard. My driver told me this was the first time it has rained like this all summer in Greece. Without the rain, it is possible to climb Mt. Olympus in one day. However with the Rain, scrambling to Mytikas is extremely dangerous. Granite is extremely slippery while wet and the falls are easily fatal. The second day only took me 5-6 hours instead of the average 9. The first day took me 2.5. If you get to Prionia at 8, and assuming you hike at a frisky pace, you can make it down by 18:00.  Hiking Mt. Olympus in one day is rarely seen and everyone you talk to will not recommend it. As I said, falls from the side of Mytikas are easily fatal and it would be wise to climb with a fresh mind and body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will I have elevation sickness?&lt;/strong&gt;
A Romanian guy that I hiked to Refuge A with left shortly after taking a nap there. He said he felt sick in the head and the stomach. Since we arrived at Refuge A around noon time, he could afford to hike down again. If you arrive at night, then the hike down will be more difficult. Hike to Refuge A and see how well you feel. I had a slight headache but it disappeared after a large dinner and nap. The next day, two other people that I met on the mountain also left instead of hiking to Skolio as they had planned because of elevation sickness as well. So plan ahead, and always be wary of your health. Your safety should always be the first priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How should I prepare for an overnight stay?&lt;/strong&gt;
Because I had originally prepared to hike Mt. Olympus in one day, I did not prepare for an overnight stay. Things that I didn&amp;rsquo;t bring and should have: contact lenses, toothbrush, toothpaste, phone charger. Although I forgot to bring a charger, there were other people there who were nice enough to lend me one. The people there are extremely nice and friendly and will help you in anyway possible. You, of course, should do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pants or shorts?&lt;/strong&gt;
I only wore shorts because I thought that it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be that cold at the top. I was wrong. Wearing shorts didn&amp;rsquo;t kill me but it was quite uncomfortable as 5C and the wind is actually quite cold. Wear pants or even better, bring pants that can turn into shorts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will my camera work at such cold temperatures?&lt;/strong&gt;
Your phone may not work at very cold temperatures, as in the case with my iPhone 6s. At about halfway to Skala from Refuge A, my phone would just die even though it had 30% battery left. I had to keep it tight against my stomach and hope that it would heat up enough so that I could take a few pictures. I was able to take a few from time to time, but for the most part, my phone was inoperable. Bring a camera that can withstand low temperatures to prevent these troubles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;final_verdict&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-verdict&#34;&gt;Final Verdict&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of all the hikes that I&amp;rsquo;ve been on so far, (Mt. Fuji, Half Dome, other less popular hikes) Mt. Olympus has been my favorite experience of them all. First, the people were amazing. The guys that I hiked up the mountain with were extremely friendly and even though two of them did not speak English at all (Romanian and Greek), they were nice and fun people to be around. The people at the Refuge were really good-natured and friendly as well. You will meet people from all over the world and it seems like hikers are just really nice people in general. I became friends with 2 Greeks, 1 Romanian fellow, 3 Austrians, 2 Germans as well as 2 dogs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The views were absolutely stunning. I finally understand what people mean by &amp;lsquo;some views are worth dying for&amp;rsquo; now. Waking up to the sunrise over Litochoro and the sea was absolutely magical. The hike up the mountain was phenomenal as well. I chose hiking Mt. Olympus over going to the Santorini islands and I think it was definitely worth it. Even though the sights were jaw-dropping, hiking isn&amp;rsquo;t just about the sights, it&amp;rsquo;s about the entire experience that includes the people, the smells, and the feelings that you experience through the hike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This trip I went to Athens, Litochoro, Rome, Florence, Venice and Milan and out of all of the sights and people I met in those cities, I think the hike to Mytikas will definitely be the most memorable experience of them all. Much better than just going somewhere and looking at historical monuments, being able to climb the &amp;ldquo;Mountain of the gods&amp;rdquo; that the Greeks have deemed as the location of their Mythological gods was the most amazing thing that I have done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you ever have the chance to go to Greece and have the love for hiking/nature, then you have to hike Mt. Olympus, even if it isn&amp;rsquo;t to Mytikas. (Skolio is much easier but will be just as memorable). If I can convince even one of you to experience what I experienced sometime during your lifetime, then all of this was worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ciao.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building My Own Headphone Amp</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/amp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/amp/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/amp/IMG_1212.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Amp&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The finished Objective2 headphone amp&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a music enthusiast, I&amp;rsquo;ve always been in the pursuit of the best sound replication devices. As I researched more and more about headphones and the amazing world of sound replication, I kept reading about these things called amps and DACs (digital-to-analag converters). For a long time, I simply ignored those terms as I felt that they were too advanced for the average Joe. They seemed too complicated and only for the professional studio recorders or niche audiophile market. Some people are fine with their Apple Earpods, but seeing how much I enjoyed listening to music, I decided to further delve into this world of sound reproductions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;table-of-contents&#34;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#why&#34;&gt;Why&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what&#34;&gt;What&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how&#34;&gt;How&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;why&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to play music, one must have an amp. Each computer and device that is able to play music have a built-in amp in the housing of the device. However, if you plan to use higher-fidelity earphones that have a higher output impendence (32ohms), then an external amp would be useful if not necessary to increase the volume without unnecessary distortion. As you may know, increasing the volume to high levels will not only cause damage to the headphones but will also cause enormous distortion. A good amp not only provides sufficient power to increase the volume of the sound but also do so without losing noticeable sound quality. An external headphone amp offers more space that can provide better circuitry and a stronger power supply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Headphones such as the Sennheiser HD 600 and HD 800 have output impedances of 300 ohms. In order to properly drive these, you will need an amp. Without an amp, the sound even at the highest volume on your laptop will sound weak and the highs and lows will be greatly lacking. Many bass sounds with low frequencies may not be heard at all. Other earphones such as the Earpods or convenience store headphones have very low output impedances 32 so they appear to be very loud even when only driven by your laptop or phone. Most headphones under $100 will not require an amp as they are meant for the average consumer who only cares about providing sound and not high-quality playback. Many people who ended up trying a better pair of headphones with an external amp have  repeatedly said that it was like listening to a different song. They notice many sounds and background instruments that they have never heard before. And the best thing about this is that you don&amp;rsquo;t need a special pair of ears or training to hear the difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/amp/IMG_1207.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Amp&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;what&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is so good about the Objective2?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story: &lt;a href=&#34;https://spectrum.ieee.org/tech-history/silicon-revolution/nwavguy-the-audio-genius-who-vanished&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NwAvGuy&lt;/a&gt; is an engineer who is also very interested in audio. He searched and searched for the perfect headphone amplifier but couldn&amp;rsquo;t find one. He wanted an amp quiet enough you could use it with the most sensitive in-ear monitors but also powerful enough to drive a full-size can with 600-ohm impedance as well as magnetic-planar models. He also wanted an amp that had a low enough output impedance as to prevent frequency response and bass damping problems. And on top of that, it should be portable powered by DC and also be able to be powered through an AC wall adapter. He wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to find one, so he decided to make his own and make it affordable as well. And as it turns out, if you cut the cost from marketing and unnecessary bling to make it look expensive but have subpar performance, you can create not only an affordable amp but an amp that is portable and offers the best sound quality that compares to the $1600 Benchmark DAC1 Pre in a listening comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DAC1 is something of a favorite in the audiophile headphone community. A lot of subjective critics, and those who have measured it, really love it. So it’s all the more satisfying nobody has yet been able to tell the O2 from the DAC1’s headphone amp. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nwavguy.blogspot.com/2011/07/o2-headphone-amp.html#measurements&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, how do you compare amps? There are so many factors to compare so how can I possibly state that the objective 2 is the best amp? Aren&amp;rsquo;t things like this subjective rather than &amp;ldquo;objective&amp;rdquo;? Let me restate: the objective 2 is the best amp under the $500 range in every objective category for only a fifth of that price. Yeah, you heard me, that&amp;rsquo;s $100. I got mine for $59 by building it myself by purchasing the DIY kit. You can even buy the components yourself and assemble it for about $30. Now you&amp;rsquo;re going to ask me, how can an amp that is made using $30 of components possibly compare to a $500 state-of-the-art amp??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are just after reviews, you can take a look at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.head-fi.org/products/jds-labs-assembled-objective2-headphone-amplifier&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Head-fi is a site dedicated to audiophiles and reviews of what they call &amp;ldquo;head gear&amp;rdquo; which includes earphones, headphones, amplifiers, DACs, and all sorts of other music-listening peripherals. It is rated the #1 desktop amp with 100% positive reviews. Mind you, the reviewers on this site are all obsessed with music fidelity so they are not your average amazon customer who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know what they are getting at. Some of these reviews go into the extreme depth that includes a breakdown  of the amp to even its bare circuit design. The sounds are described with terms such as &amp;ldquo;bright&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;decent texture&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;well-extended with no roll-off&amp;rdquo; Many of these reviewers have been testing audio equipment for years and own many pairs of high-quality headphones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are, however, after the solid facts, below I have included the evidence that tests and compares the technicalities of various amps that range up to $450.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nwavguy.blogspot.com/2011/07/o2-headphone-amp.html#measurements&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://nwavguy.blogspot.com/2011/07/o2-headphone-amp.html#measurements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;how&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did I build the Objective2? Now this is the fun part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve convinced you to buy the Objective2, you must be asking: where can I get one? &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jdslabs.com/products/35/objective2-headphone-amplifier/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; you can buy it completely assembled and enclosed in an anodized and fully polished enclosure for $129. It is also customizable for different outputs such as for different countries or 3.5mm headphone jack to 6.35mm (1/4in) headphone jack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, there is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jdslabs.com/products/167/objective2-headphone-amplifier-b-stock/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;refurbished version for $99.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find $129 a bit too expensive to throw down for an amp, then I suggest the DIY option. For just $59, you can purchase a DIY kit that contains all of the components to build the amp. Soldering required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;($59) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jdslabs.com/products/82/objective2-diy-kit/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DIY Kit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/amp/IMG_1205.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Amp&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;($9) 2 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Tenergy-Centura-Self-Discharge-Rechargeable-Batteries/dp/B003QUNYQI/ref=sr_1_10_a_it?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;amp;qid=1469762948&amp;amp;amp;sr=8-10&amp;amp;amp;keywords=9v+rechargeable+batteries&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;9V batteries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
or/and&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;($12.99) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jdslabs.com/products/147/us-15vac-power-adapter-for-objective2/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15V AC Power Adapter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only con about this DIY is that there is no enclosure. If you wish you can 3D print one or order the enclosure from the website as well.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;($12.99) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jdslabs.com/products/94/aluminum-enclosure-for-objective2/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Top/side enclosure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;($9.99) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jdslabs.com/products/34/machined-objective2-front-panel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Front panel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;($9.99) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jdslabs.com/products/163/machined-objective2-odac-rear-plate-ac-usb-jacks/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rear plate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for $99, you can get your own amp!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/amp/IMG_2449.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Amp&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/amp/IMG_1203.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Amp&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The DIY kit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks Rui Wang @ Rays Hobby&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Important Thing That I Learned This Summer</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/passion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/passion/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve often been told that passion leads to success. It is one thing to hear a quote and another thing entirely to experience it firsthand. This summer, I was hired as an intern by Rui (pronounced REY) Wang, a computer science professor at the University of Massachusetts Amherst as well as the founder of Ray&amp;rsquo;s Hobby and OpenSprinkler. During these three months, I learned a handful of technical skills as well as professional skills such as problem solving and communication. But most importantly, working in the business led me to begin my own business. Not one out of desperation, but one out of passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passion for hardware gadgets and a desire to improve other people&amp;rsquo;s lives is what drove Rui to begin his business. Like Facebook and  Snapchat, each of their founders had a certain focus in mind, whether it was to create an online platform where you could look up other people, or to develop a system for sending explicit pictures, these businesses didn&amp;rsquo;t begin with the goal of making money in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the majority of my life, my life goal was to make money. Everything that I wanted to do in life seemed to be revolved around money. In order to finance an adventure to the peak of Mt. Everest, I would need anywhere between $50k and $100k. To be able to invest, I would at least need a few thousand to make it worthwhile. To design my own house, I would need to purchase a house and have the time and money to finance a study in interior design. Though these pursuits of mine don&amp;rsquo;t directly need money, in order to make time for these things I would need to be able to sustain myself while I spend time on these things.a And because of these pursuits, my goal inevitably became to make as much money as I could. That was also my initial thought process to becoming a computer science major. After working at Rui&amp;rsquo;s and coming close to finding something that I am passionate about, I realized that the joy that money brings is much more inferior to the joy that doing something you love brings. However, it&amp;rsquo;s also equally important to find a passion that can provide enough money to sustain yourself and your family. If you happen to be passionate about a field that is employable and financially rewarding, count yourself lucky. If not, then you may have to continue searching for that passion that is just right for you. I truly believe that everyone will be able to find that passion. With the world so big and there being so many things to do, if you can&amp;rsquo;t find one, remember that you can always create one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while, I make new revelations and this summer my revelation is: finding a passion is more important than making money. I&amp;rsquo;ve known the facts for a long time. Passion brings happiness, &amp;hellip; but just like many people, they don&amp;rsquo;t accept it because they are stuck in between a state of doubt and one of not being able to find their passion. I am here to convince you that if you want to be happy, and if you want your life to be meaningful, the goal is to find your passion in life. I believe that everyone&amp;rsquo;s meaning of life is determined through their passion. No matter how long it takes you to find it, you should settle for anything less than your life passion. It&amp;rsquo;s possible for some people like Rui to have found their passion as a child. Others discover their passion in high school or in college. Many people don&amp;rsquo;t discover their passion until they&amp;rsquo;ve already started working but I believe that everybody will find it. We all have a purpose in this world and if we aren&amp;rsquo;t predetermined with one, we have the ability to give ourselves one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up next: Looking to read about the business I mentioned at the start? Well, don&amp;rsquo;t fret because it&amp;rsquo;s coming out next.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Became Independent at 18</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/independence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/independence/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following is a story about my dad&amp;rsquo;s iron fist and how he guided me to complete independence at a tender age of 18 and what I did about it.&lt;/em&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-you-turn-18-you-re-on-your-own&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;When you turn 18, you&amp;rsquo;re on your own.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When you turn 18, you&amp;rsquo;re on your own,&amp;rdquo; my dad had told me time and time again ever since I was old enough to begin worrying about college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He told me that he would only cover my school tuition. (I&amp;rsquo;m plenty privileged to have parents willing to cover my college tuition. I realize that many people do not have this privilege.) I was 14 when he told me that for the first time. And like any other 14-year-old teen, I brushed it aside and comforted myself that I would be fine and worry about it when the time came. When I turned 18 and went to college, he kept his word about only paying for my tuition. From that point onward, I was on my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &amp;ldquo;on your own&amp;rdquo; thing meant that I had to find housing, food on my own and finance it on my own. I had nobody else to rely on but my friends at times. Either I would find a mean of making money, or I would starve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;spring-break&#34;&gt;Spring Break&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first challenge for me came during spring break. My school was about to close within a few days for a week-long of spring break and I had no clue on where I would stay and how I would be able to eat. When I had called my dad and asked for advice, he told me that it was my own responsibility, and not his. I was so angry and in despair at the time that I outright hung up on him. I was 18 at the time and that was when I finally realized the reality of having to survive on my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How the hell was I supposed to find housing and food in a few days?&amp;rdquo;, I thought, trying to stop myself from punching a wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friends all had places to go, with their parents to finance them. Most of the friends I made in college would go home since they were in-state. My international friends would from high school would either travel stayed in the US or also go home. Others stayed in their college dorms, which wasn&amp;rsquo;t an option for me because UMass Amherst closes down over breaks. The feeling I had when I realized I was all alone in this is something I will never forget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I had to put together a plan. I weighed the options. I looked at Airbnb rentals, I looked at houses and apartments around the area on Facebook and Craigslist, I weighed the option of living at a relative&amp;rsquo;s or family friend&amp;rsquo;s place. Each of these options would require me to work to pay off the living expenses and find a way to buy groceries without a car. Living at a friend&amp;rsquo;s relatives place or family friends for free would be ignoble. I would have to work for them or find work elsewhere and pay them for the rent. But, I had no car so I would have to find other means of transportation to commute to and from work. In the end, an idea struck me and that was to see if any of my friends&amp;rsquo; colleges didn&amp;rsquo;t close over the break and if I could stay with them. Luckily, one of my friends who was attending Berklee College of Music in Boston had space for me in his dorm. I am indebted to him for providing a place for me to stay for the week. Without him, I don&amp;rsquo;t know what I would have done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summer-the-real-struggle&#34;&gt;Summer: The Real Struggle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If that experience wasn&amp;rsquo;t bearing enough, the real challenge was when summertime came around the corner. This time I didn&amp;rsquo;t need to find a place to live for one week. I had to find somewhere to stay for four months! This meant finding housing, a job, and a method of feeding myself. Those were the only three things on my mind. Being able to see my friends? That thought wasn&amp;rsquo;t even in my head at the time. With some advice from my parents, I came up with three primary plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get an internship and move to wherever my internship was.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask a family friend or relative if I could stay with them and find a job nearby to pay the rent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take summer classes and find housing through my university.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These seemed like plausible plans. But when I took a closer look, I discovered many issues. How would I commute to work without a car? Where would I find a job? How would I pay for my university housing in advance? As I worried about these question night after night, one day, something magical happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My computer science professor for the spring semester was hiring an intern to help him out with a personal hardware business and he picked me for the job. I replied to his e-mail soon after he sent out his job offer to the class. and I sent him my qualifications. It was only after I met with him that he said that I would also be able to stay in a guest room in his house because I had nowhere else to go. Being independent meant that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t bounded to any place. I could live wherever I wanted.  This gave me an advantage over other candidates who could not live in Amherst or had to commute. The fact that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t bounded to any single location has become an advantage in my career time and time again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t being the top of my class that got me the job. It was the simple fact that my professor recognized me by name because I had attended his office hours more often than other students. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t the one of the top seven in the class who received an A+ in the class and received citations because of that. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t even in the top 53 in the class who received As. I was only a student who attended more office hours and made an attempt to talk to my professor after and out of the classroom and answer and ask questions in class. I always sat in the middle of the 2nd row and was always one of the first students there. Though I wasn&amp;rsquo;t the smartest, I had the diligence and trusted myself that I would always do the right thing. My professor picked me for the sole fact that I was the only name that he recognized out of all the e-mails he received.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You can’t connect the dots looking forward; you can only connect them looking backward. So you have to trust that the dots will somehow connect in your future. You have to trust in something — your gut, destiny, life, karma, whatever. This approach has never let me down, and it has made all the difference in my life.&amp;rdquo; – Steve Jobs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In retrospect, if I attempted to get a higher grade by relying only on myself and skipping the office hours, or if I had sat in class and scrolled through Facebook, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be where I am right now. Each choice that I made was a dot and now that I am working with my professor day-after-day, I can say, once again, that my choices have not let me down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;note&#34;&gt;Note&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am in no way promoting trading self-studying for office hours or saying that grades are not important. All I am saying is to make the best of your situation and to trust in your choices. Additionally, office hours and sitting at the front of a class are both easy and great opportunities to get to know your professors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to teach one independence and responsibility. Experience is the best teacher. My parents trusted their judgment to let me survive on my own, and for that, I am grateful beyond words.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Don&#39;t Have a Passion</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/passionless/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/passionless/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What is your passion?&amp;rdquo; my professor, Rui (pronounced REY) Wang, asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, the question seemed simple. Yet, after pondering it, I realized I didn&amp;rsquo;t have an answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about a lot of things&amp;rdquo;, I tried to explain. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about the environment and&amp;hellip; about other things too!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compared to Rui&amp;rsquo;s level of passion for his hardware business, my passion for the environment felt like peanuts. It was only an interest. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a satisfactory answer.  As the days flew by, I had continued to think about this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One evening, I stumbled upon a TED talks playlist named, &amp;ldquo;Talks to watch when you don&amp;rsquo;t know what to do with your life&amp;rdquo;. Since I had nothing better to do, I decided to watch the first one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click the picture below to watch it. (I didn&amp;rsquo;t think it was worth watching.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/larry_smith_why_you_will_fail_to_have_a_great_career?language=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://pi.tedcdn.com/r/pe.tedcdn.com/images/ted/0ba3ef25abbdde1e88c829366cc1838a1e58d5e2_1600x1200.jpg?op=%5E&amp;amp;c=1280%2C720&amp;amp;gravity=t&amp;amp;u%5Br%5D=2&amp;amp;u%5Bs%5D=0.5&amp;amp;u%5Ba%5D=0.8&amp;amp;u%5Bt%5D=0.03&amp;amp;quality=82&amp;amp;w=1280&amp;amp;h=720&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;quot;Why you will fail to have a great career&amp;quot;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Larry Smith: Why you will fail to have a great career&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was inspiring was that it also talked about passion. It reminded me of the chat that I had with my professor. He talked about how most peoples&amp;rsquo; careers fail because of a lack of passion. People with passion in the field that your in will always be more successful. You may earn more than them if you put enough of your time into it, but enjoy doing what they do, while you will still be searching for your life&amp;rsquo;s purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more I thought about it, the more I drove myself into a dead end. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t passionate about anything. I enjoyed doing almost everything from a young child. I enjoyed playing all the sports, found them all to have different aspects that I was passionate about, and to this day, I still enjoy a large variety of topics. I may be a computer scientist in school, but outside of school, I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about the arts, music, literature and humanitarian subjects. I enjoy writing in my free time, reading, and reading some more. I find all sorts of stuff interesting and I have an insatiable curiosity to learn more, no matter what it is.  Whenever I travel, I enjoy engaging in conversations with strangers. I&amp;rsquo;m genuinely curious to learn more about them and what they do. The more I thought about it, the more I began to realize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Could anything can become a passion?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Does your passion have to be in a certain field or activity?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Could you just be passionate about learning?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way that my professor defines a passion is something that you are willing to do for the rest of your life. There is nothing that I would be willing to do for the rest of my life, except learning. I can&amp;rsquo;t do one thing only. coding? writing? reading? philosophy? economics? math? no way. Although the one problem that I now realize is that learning as a passion does not make any money. Well, directly that is. Indirectly, it could generate income based on my knowledge and skills that I develop through learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or I haven&amp;rsquo;t found my passion yet. That is another possibility. Based on my past and how well I know myself, I won&amp;rsquo;t find a distinct one. But who knows? Anything&amp;rsquo;s possible, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bit about my professor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only is he a tenure-track professor, he also runs a business from his house. He creates open-source hardware. It started off as a hack to solve a home problem, but after he posted it onto his blog, it got a lot more attention. People began asking him if the product was for sale, so he decided to turn it into a business. He tells me that he only does it because it makes him happy and that he is passionate about it. He told me he wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have started a business if it was only for the money. He worked on the business every day throughout the summer and has never viewed it as work. He takes extra enjoyment in helping make people&amp;rsquo;s lives easier. This is what I call passion. This is also what many people would consider success.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My New Housemate is a Professor</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/professor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/professor/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;My freshmen chapter ends here and a new chapter begins.  Today is my first day as housemates with my professor, &lt;a href=&#34;https://people.cs.umass.edu/~ruiwang/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rui (pronounced REY) Wang from UMass Amherst&lt;/a&gt;. I will be working with him on his &lt;a href=&#34;https://rayshobby.net/wordpress/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;open-source hardware business&lt;/a&gt; for the next 4 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This opportunity is a godsend. The fact that I am making money is peanuts compared to what else I may gain from this invaluable experience. Spending so much time with an associate professor from the Computer Science department will be extremely beneficial to my development as a computer science major and as a student of academia. The information that I will be able to gain through talking to him, and working with him will hopefully give me a keener insight on my future as well help pave my academic path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I expect to be learning a lot, I will only post the things that I find are the most valuable to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why do professors continue to do research, long after they get their Ph.D.? Because there is a problem that they want to solve. It is something that they are passionate about, and like a game or any other puzzle with an endgame in mind, it is something that they want to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nothing is as easy as it seems. For me, attending military camp at the Forest Hill Military Academy in Kentucky was one of the toughest experiences of my life. For my professor, it was getting his tenure. In order to get tenure, you have to do research for six years, work every moment, every hour of the day. He said that after those six years, nothing could frustrate him anymore because that was the toughest time for him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I had no other life besides work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never realized how hard it was to obtaining tenure or the amount of work you have to put in after college and in grad school. Everybody sees  the awards that people obtain, but seldom do people see the hard work behind every title.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks Amigos</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/friends/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve all heard this quote before:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You are the average of the five people you spend the most time with.” – Jim Rohn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do your friends define who you are? Take a moment to ponder this thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, the answer is no. You are yourself and there is nobody who can learn who you are by being around your friends. We are each too unique to be defined that way. Conversely, what if I told you that your friends shaped you? The people you&amp;rsquo;ve met and the conversations that you&amp;rsquo;ve had with your friends with nurtured and shaped the person you are today. In that case, your friends have defined you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do believe that a person&amp;rsquo;s friends and experiences shape them. However, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be possible to know someone by knowing their friends. You can never know all his/her friends. Even if you did, you would have to understand them all and all their friends. When a friend of yours has a very questionable friend such as an alcoholic, you can&amp;rsquo;t judge either of them. It would be doing them an injustice. There is nothing you can tell from a situation like that. People&amp;rsquo;s friends shape them, but you can&amp;rsquo;t define a person by only observing their friends. You need to take this matter to a personal level. Whoever it is, I am sure that they&amp;rsquo;re much different than their friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am dedicating this post to not friends in general, but my personal friends. Without my friends, I would be an empty shell. They have made me. Additionally, after 18 years I&amp;rsquo;ve come to realize that my closest friends will always be the ones who are the most like me. My dad once told me that short people and tall people can become friends rather easily because such differences give them more to talk about. that is true for him, but from personal experience, I find that to be untrue in my life. Differences separate people, they don&amp;rsquo;t bring people together. Similarities are the things that bring people closer together, creating bonds for life. You can talk to people very different to you, you may be intrigued by how they think and their backgrounds, but you will never be able to bond with them as well as you can bond with people that share the same story as you. People with similar stories and families have a bond that is deeper than friendship. Their stories are interconnected. They run a similar fate and are on the same plane. No matter what happens, there will always be a link that runs through them.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Material Possessions vs. Experiences</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/experience/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Departure.
You don&amp;rsquo;t really feel the emotions of leaving a place that has been your home until about 4 days before the date of departure. Everyone talks about it long before that phase like they are sad and sentimental, but you don&amp;rsquo;t really feel it until it&amp;rsquo;s right upon you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting yesterday, I&amp;rsquo;ve begun to feel it. All the emotions slowly building up, in addition to the fact that you are physically also preparing yourself, packing, and going through all of your belongings, things that you haven&amp;rsquo;t touched in years. You want to take everything that reminds you of your past, but you realize that they aren&amp;rsquo;t really of any use in college. They will just take up space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experiences however, are the things that will be kept with you no matter where you go. They will always be in your memories, unless you have amnesia of course. My mom once told me that she never buys souvenirs because after a while they don&amp;rsquo;t mean anything and they just take up space. Instead when we travel, she splurges on whatever food she can get her hands on. I agreed with her, but thought that maybe some possessions can also bring you happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experiences &amp;gt; possessions. Period. This isn&amp;rsquo;t just something I came up with. There&amp;rsquo;s actually been lots of research and studies done on what leaves behind the most happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Buy Experiences, Not Things @ The Atlantic
 • Want To Buy Happiness? Purchase An Experience. @ Forbes 
• People Who Spend Money On Experiences Instead Of Things Are Much Happier @ Elite Daily 
• The Science Of Why You Should Spend Your Money On Experiences, Not Things @ Fast Company&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• tl;dr The happiness that you derive from purchasing a possession fades drastically over time.  Experiences, however stay in your memories and can even affect you as a person. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• In fact, even bad experiences make a good story. (Shoutout to A.C.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above are just some articles that I came across. There are many more supporting this point. So in the future, instead of buying some luxurious watch or car, I&amp;rsquo;m going to invite my friends to some resort in Honolulu for a month. Relaxing on the beach, drinking strawberry daiquiris, dancing, eating good food, swimming, and just having a good time with friends,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings me to my next point. How many experiences has Bill Gates sacrificed to make all that money? Mark Zuckerberg? Warren Buffet? I think too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To become somebody with that wealth, sacrifices must be made. Some simple ones are wearing the same thing everyday. In order to come up with more time to spend on coming up with new business models and managing their companies, many billionaires began to live frugal and minimalistic lifestyles. Wearing the same thing everyday is just the tip of the iceberg. When people talk about Warren Buffet is still living in his flat in Omaha, people tend to think that it&amp;rsquo;s because he&amp;rsquo;s such a good guy, instead of splurging, he gives the rest of his money to charity. That is true only to a certain extent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other reason why he does that is because of his lifestyle. Becoming a billionaire means not buying the next laptop that comes out. It means you don&amp;rsquo;t go on vacations when you get a $5000 paycheck. Nor does it mean you can buy that pair of shoes that just look so good on you. You save. You don&amp;rsquo;t spend at all. Then you invest. Having what it takes to become a billionaire means sacrificing a lot of joy in your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the one of the most enjoyable things in life are sports. Think about how hyped people get when they hear that they are playing dodgeball for PE class. Sports are one of the greatest gifts in life. Those billionaires don&amp;rsquo;t have time for sports. There are even some investors who sleep 3 hours a day just to finish all his work. I may be wrong, but I&amp;rsquo;m starting to think that all those sacrifices just aren&amp;rsquo;t worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the money you earn is just possessions. You don&amp;rsquo;t need that much money for experiences. Possessions are generally more expensive than experiences. I bet there are many people out there who have lived much happier lives than Steve Jobs. True, there is a saying that happy people are happy no matter how much money they have. But, to acquire that much money will surely hack away at your health and time. The final verdict? Balance.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climbing The North Face</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2015/yosemite/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2015/yosemite/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been nearly a whole year since I summited the half dome in Yosemite Valley National Park. One of my favorite hiking adventures of all time, below is the journal entry that I wrote after the hike.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;table-of-contents&#34;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#the_ascent&#34;&gt;The Ascent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#the_descent&#34;&gt;The Descent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#review&#34;&gt;Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#afterword&#34;&gt;Afterword&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1429516387459-9891b7b96c78?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=1950&amp;amp;q=80&#34; alt=&#34;Half Dome, Yosemite National Park&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Half Dome, Yosemite National Park, California. Look familiar? That&amp;rsquo;s because it&amp;rsquo;s a default desktop wallpaper for Apple computers and it was the inspiration for the North Face logo.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/DhZQlaqzddg?t=445&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://stevec.smugmug.com/Hiking/Half-Dome-hike-July-9-2006/1005379/80937752_ZJ44q-O.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Half Dome cables&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Yes, I would say it was quite steep. Click on the picture above to see a video of somebody climbing the cables.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9/1/2015&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s currently 3:28AM and I want to record my thoughts and experiences before I forget them. Up until now, I have not had the chance to get on my computer. Seldom does that happen to people, but it seems to happen to me quite often. I&amp;rsquo;m one of those kinds of people that could probably not use the internet unless they had to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;the_ascent&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-ascent&#34;&gt;The Ascent&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8/31/2015&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My alarm went off at 5:30AM. The sounds of my neighbors woke me up many times throughout the night. When I finally fell into a deep sleep at 2 AM, I had to leave for the hike. During the night I had many dreams that I wish I could&amp;rsquo;ve written down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/yosemite/IMG_0461.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Packing for the hike&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/yosemite/IMG_0465.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Packing for the hike 2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dressed and set out with my parents at 6AM, eating my cold turkey sandwich on the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first stop was Happy Isles Nature Center, a.k.a. a shuttle bus stop. The first part was only three-quarters of a mile or 1.2km. After crossing the Happy Isles Bridge, I parted ways with my parents and took the Mist Trail leading to Vernal Falls, then Nevada Falls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the way, I met many people. At first, it felt weird being greeted by and greeting everyone I met on the trail. Later, it became instinctual for me. I realized that it was usually the casual American day hikers that greeted me back. The hardcore hikers were too focused, and the foreigners were probably alien to being greeted by strangers all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first two waterfalls were only the beginning. The real hike was little Yosemite Valley (approx. 4 miles). During this time, I was almost completely alone, having an abundant amount of time to think and sing and do whatever I wanted&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember having many interesting thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was especially interesting was how during the hike I began to remember so many things from my past. Recalling specific moments, such as waking up in the morning before dawn every day during military camp, and hiking Mirror Lake in Oregon as a child. It felt euphoric. It was like a rollercoaster of emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/yosemite/IMG_0447-PANO.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Panorama&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;the_descent&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-descent&#34;&gt;The Descent&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did meet a guy on the way back who seemed to be on the same schedule as me. We reached the top at the same time, and after resting separately we ended up coming down at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We traveled fast. There weren&amp;rsquo;t that many people on the trail, yet we were still passing people every ten minutes. We never introduced ourselves to each other, but we chatted plenty on the descent, as a result, I learned many things about him. Before living in Utah and doing research in biotech, he attended Baylor College of Medicine in Texas to pursue his Ph.D. in microbiology. He did research on HIV for 5 years. He attended Oregon State University for his undergraduate studies where he double majored in environmental engineering as well as something else. Additionally, he introduced himself to me as an avid gamer. Although the game I  played the most at the time was League of Legends, we talked about his favorites such as Deadspace and Dark Souls. He told me that he used to be a marathon runner. A while back, he quit his job to relax for a while before having some surgeries. He&amp;rsquo;d been traveling across the states on a goal to tour all the national parks. Although it may seem somewhat arbitrary and insignificant, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but notice that he had the same pose as me of a pic when I posed for a picture on top of Mt. Fuji. One knee kneeling, with one elbow draping down on the other. From that act, I thought I could relate to him somehow in personality. Also, while descending the cables, I realized we had much in common. Not where we lived and where we were from but also in personality. It was pretty great. Talking to him for the first time was natural and not awkward at all. It felt as if we had been friends for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way back, I chose the John Muir Trail instead of the Mist Trail in an attempt for some change in scenery. That was when I split up with my travel friend. It was the right choice. I got a surplus of more splendid sights and even got the chance to rest and wash my feet near a stream. It was chill. With 4 miles left, I ran out of water. That meant no food either because my energy snacks actually dehydrate you. Some nice travelers saved me though by throwing me a water bottle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/yosemite/IMG_0487.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time I got down, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t even that ecstatic to have made it to the top of the Half Dome and to have completed the adventure. I was too exhausted. Looking at the pictures I took seemed unnaturally serene to me. It felt the Mt. Fuji hike. It&amp;rsquo;s like life. After trekking so far and persevering so much, you make it to the top. But then, you don&amp;rsquo;t even feel accomplished because after a while it becomes who you are. If you spend 20 years of your life becoming rich (no matter much money that is), and you finally become rich, you may hurrah one time, but then after that, that feeling of accomplishment fades and you label yourself as &amp;ldquo;rich&amp;rdquo; and move onto other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, after hiking I was soo tired. My dad congratulated me, yet I ignored him. Too tired. On the way down I even stopped saying hi to people. Anyways, I took a shower, ate and immediately went to sleep. Didn&amp;rsquo;t even move my stuff off of my bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;review&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;review&#34;&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, this adventure was an amazing experience. Compared to Mt. Fuji, it was easier. When I hiked Mt. Fuji, I was operating on an all-nighter, improper food, less water, a more drastic range of temperatures it was in the middle of the night. Additionally, people surrounding me were complaining every five minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the Half Dome, I had more rest, preparation, equipment, a Camelbak, it was during the daytime and nobody to complain to me. It was me. I noticed that when you are alone, you don&amp;rsquo;t complain. Not only is it because I have nobody really to complain to, but I also toughen up. It&amp;rsquo;s like I&amp;rsquo;m competing against a better version of myself. Whenever I complain I noticed that half the time it&amp;rsquo;s to fit in because everyone else around me is complaining as well. One of my friends, Max, does a great job of not complaining when a workout gets tough. For lack of proper terms, he mans up, like me when I am alone. I guess I have to stop learning from the bad habits of others and be myself. At the start of the hike, I thought this hike was going to be harder than Mt. Fuji because I had to hike it alone. But I was wrong. It was WAY easier because I was alone. Nobody to slow me down, to mess up my pacing and to disturb me from my thoughts. If I wanted to talk to people, I could still talk to people on the way. What I did was entirely up to me and I didn&amp;rsquo;t even have to stay with them the entire way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Climbing Mt. Fuji, I had to make decisions for the other three as I was the one who planned the hike and if it was a bad decision, the blame was on me. We waited repeatedly for my friend named Henry and another friend, Andrew, being the good guy that he stayed behind to wait for him. On the way down, Andrew and Henry had looks of such despair and pain on their faces that it seemed like they were about to collapse. And Edward, the third friend, was too fatigued and annoyed to talk. If I had hiked Mt. Fuji like I had hiked Half Dome with that guy, we would&amp;rsquo;ve made it down in no time and not even felt shitty. To be frank, my friends weren&amp;rsquo;t probably used to pushing themselves so hard physically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now Half Dome was completely chill. I had an amazing hike. Unless I find the right partner, it might be better I hike alone. It seems that sometimes other people you back. Plus, the alone time was extra special. Talking to my travel pal, the descent went by in a blink of an eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;afterword&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;afterword&#34;&gt;Afterword&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well now that this hike is over, I don&amp;rsquo;t know what else is in store for me this summer. Nothing can compare to this hike. I also only have seven days left until school starts! Holy cow time goes by fast. I can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s the first of September today already. That leaves me with only three more days until I check-in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow. Four more days until school. The summer that I graduated from high school is reaching the end and my next step is college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, peace out. Yosemite National Park has been the shit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In comparison with Mt. Fuji, the Half Dome hike was a hike through the true wilderness, while Fuji was a hike in a barren wasteland. To be more accurate, it was a hike up a volcanic mountain covered in rocks and dirt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Half Dome hike stats:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
15-miles round trip (24km)&lt;br&gt;
Elevation gain 4800ft (1463m)&lt;br&gt;
Average time: 11 hours My time: 9 hours&lt;br&gt;
Half Dome cables distance: 400ft (122m)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people discuss the Half Dome hike, the cables are always the main point of interest. It&amp;rsquo;s the crux of the hike, and usually the most challenging. But, I enjoyed the cables very much. It was because I was having such a blast that it didn&amp;rsquo;t feel challenging at all for me. Sure, it was slippery, and I even slipped a couple of times, but if you aren&amp;rsquo;t afraid of heights and have a decent amount of upper-body strength, it&amp;rsquo;s a piece of cake. Another contributing factor that made it easy for me was that there was a traffic jam on the cables, so I took a break every few steps. It forced me to make pace and made the whole thing much easier. Oh, and for gloves, I had a pair of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00AHEQ35K/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Black Diamond Craig Climbing Gloves&lt;/a&gt; that I got from Amazon for $20. They were quite handy (pun intended). I saw some people climbing without gloves. Now that&amp;rsquo;s crazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least people don&amp;rsquo;t die on Mt. Fuji though. People die each year on the Half Dome. I guess that makes Half Dome quite the hike.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Brain Hack To Accomplish More</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2015/steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2015/steps/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you don’t feel like going to the gym. For one reason or another, the real reason is that you’re too lazy and don’t feel like it. Don’t make excuses. But that’s another point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listen up, because I’m going to teach you a way that has made everything for me easier. It works for anything that you’ve been doing, but find yourself having trouble following through sometimes. Your brain works in strange ways and to appeal to your brain you have to take advantage of how your brain works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re feeling too lazy to do something, divide the action into steps and start with the first step. The old adage “A journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step” is spot-on. Sure this is common sense, but by taking a single step, you put into action a process that your brain has been doing before. Jumpstart your brain. Trick it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples:
For working out, sometimes you don’t feel like going to the gym. You think of the walk to the gym, putting in work, sweating and putting in more effort. An effort that you don’t have the energy for right now. So, begin with the first step. Put on your gym clothes. If you’ve been getting ready for working out for a while now, by putting on your gym clothes you will have jumpstarted your brain into getting ready to work out. Chemical reactions in your body begin to occur and you may even begin to start sweating. Each step after that will become a breeze. Researchers have published many papers about this phenomenon. An experiment verified the effectiveness of this. A group of people took placebo energy shakes. One that looked to be the same as a pre-workout that they would take half an hour before going to the gym. Even though the mixture contained nothing but coloring and flavoring, they began to sweat and get “pumped”. Taking the first steps in a process gets your body prepared,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way, it is like muscle memory. Not muscle memory but brain memory. You become so used to doing something that by doing the first step, you don’t even have to think and you do everything that follows it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use this method of mine for even much smaller things. Sometimes I will be lying in bed, not wanting to get up. I start with the single step of moving my leg. As soon as I move my leg, my body follows and I get up. It sounds simple, but it works like a charm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By doing this, I won’t ever have to procrastinate anymore. No more short-term procrastination at least. This method has worked for me 99% of the time. The only 1% of the time that it hasn’t worked for me is in the split-time that I make the decision to take the first step, I manage to convince myself that it isn’t worth doing. Once I was sore from a work-out and I was lying in bed. Instead of getting out of bed to put away my clothes as I should have, I convinced myself that I needed to rest longer because of how tired I was. Besides the times when this happens, it has been successful every other time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use this method for everything I do now. Don’t feel like doing homework? Take out the book first. Don’t feel like writing an essay, open up an empty document and put down a single word. Don’t feel like going to school, get out of bed, and get packed. Looking at the big picture isn’t always the right approach to things. Sometimes you have to take things step-by-step. Worry about what’s at hand and let things come to you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Wesley Tian</author>
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
      <content>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-wesley&#34;&gt;About Wesley&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/me.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Wesley Tian&#34;
        title=&#34;Me&#34; style=&#34;width:20%;height:20%;border-radius:5px 25px&#34; class=&#34;center&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wesley Tian is currently pursuing a B.S. in Computer Science and Data Science at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://umich.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;University of Michigan&lt;/a&gt;. He previously served as the President of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mdst.club/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Michigan Data Science Team&lt;/a&gt;, a competitive data science team funded by Google, the National Science Foundation, and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://midas.umich.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Michigan Institute of Data Science&lt;/a&gt;. Media outlets such as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/03/27/us/flint-water-lead-pipes.html?_r=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The New York Times&lt;/a&gt; and others have covered their work for social good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past few years, Wesley has worked on research and development at an Internet of things startup with &lt;a href=&#34;https://people.cs.umass.edu/~ruiwang/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rui Wang&lt;/a&gt;, machine learning research in healthcare with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www-personal.umich.edu/~wiensj/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jenna Wiens&lt;/a&gt;, and philosophy in artificial intelligence with &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.eecs.umich.edu/~rthomaso/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rich Thomason&lt;/a&gt;. Last summer, he was hired by conversational AI startup, &lt;a href=&#34;https://clinc.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Clinc&lt;/a&gt;, to improve their machine learning models. This summer, he will be working at Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was born in Mountain View, California, and then moved to Oregon, Taiwan, Shanghai, Massachusetts, and finally, Michigan. He spent the first two years of his undergrad in Amherst, MA, first studying Environmental Science, then Computer Science and Mathematics. He thanks these moves for his openness to different perspectives and helping form many of his unique thoughts. Outside of school and work, he enjoys reading, writing, and hiking. His favorite hikes include the Half Dome in Yosemite National Park, Mt. Olympus in Greece, and Mt. Fuji in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-this-site&#34;&gt;About This Site&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made this blog because I want to get better at writing. I also want to share what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from my real-life experiences with other people, just as others have shared with me (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;www.pgbovine.net&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Phillip Guo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;blog.samaltman.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sam Altman&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;paulgraham.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Paul Graham&lt;/a&gt;). This blog is intended cover a smorgasbord of topics – from hardware projects to philosophy. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to discuss any post in detail, could you please leave a comment in the respective post&amp;rsquo;s comment section? Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags for posts include #work, #personal, #school, #internship, #project, #programming, #advice, and #travel. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to view posts with a certain tag, please navigate to wesleytian.com/tags/name_of_tag (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://wesleytian.github.io/tags/personal&#34;&gt;wesleytian.com/tags/personal&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All views expressed on this site are my own and do not represent the opinions of any entity whatsoever with which I have been, am now, or will be affiliated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 01-01-2017, this site has been viewed 6,758 times. Last updated on 6-30-2019.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>