<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wesley Tian</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Wesley Tian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 00:14:49 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>More Information is Not Always Good</title>
      <link>/posts/information/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/information/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago, I was debating with my co-workers Ty and Anish about whether or not having more information is helpful for making better decisions. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to be able to express their thoughts with high fidelity, so I will only express mine here.
Having more information does not allow us to make better decisions. In fact, a lot of the time, we can benefit from having less information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a Better SWE</title>
      <link>/posts/swe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/swe/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently realized that the skills you learn as a SWE are totally disjoint from the skills that you learn in school. Below are some of my findings.
1. Nobody knows the answer, but it&amp;rsquo;s out there somewhere. It&amp;rsquo;s up to you and only you to figure it out. That&amp;rsquo;s what the company is paying you to do. Problem-solve.
When my internship first started, I rapidly shot questions at my mentor, full-timers, and other interns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super Linux Warp Pipe</title>
      <link>/posts/pipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/pipe/</guid>
      <description>Today at work I came across a problem that I managed to solve using multiple Linux pipes. What I needed to do to solve the problem was count the frequency of words existing between a certain context.
This is a simplified version of what the input looked like:
Where is the { FRUIT apple } ? Is the { PLANT tree } within the ground ? The { FRUIT banana } ate some { FRUIT banana } .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another New Site?</title>
      <link>/posts/another-new-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/another-new-site/</guid>
      <description>So, it seems like every few months I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling discontent with my personal website, thus prompting me to overhaul my website over and over again. This frequent overhauling can be boiled down to two reasons.
 I have never really felt satisfied with the overall design and aesthetic of my personal website.
 I haven&amp;rsquo;t made up my mind about starting my blog back up again or not.
  I&amp;rsquo;ve been toying around with Jekyll and Bootstrap recently, and then I found Hugo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosting Hugo Using GitHub</title>
      <link>/posts/a-better-hugo-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-better-hugo-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>In this short tutorial, you will be creating two repositories, one that will store your Hugo source files, and one that will store the files necessary to view your website. The website repo is called public and will be inside of your source repository. This will be done by using a git submodule.
This guide requires you to have git installed, a Hugo website that you can easily clone from it&amp;rsquo;s GitHub repo, and a GitHub account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Own Cryptocurrency</title>
      <link>/projects/westcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/westcoin/</guid>
      <description>Summary:  Cryptocurrency built in Selenium on the Ethereum blockchain. Blockchain @ Michigan Workshop. WesTCoin is currently private and the exchange rate is 1 WesTCoin ~ 1 Ethereum.  Why Did I Build This? The Blockchain @ Michigan club at the University of Michigan was hosting a workshop to teach people how to create their own cryptocurrencies on the Ethereum blockchain. As as a former blockchain and cryptocurrency enthusiast, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t turn down this great opportunity to attend this workshop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First AI - A Rock, Paper, Scissors Bot </title>
      <link>/projects/rps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/rps/</guid>
      <description>Summary:  Command line AI that uses your play history to predict your next move in a game of Rock, Paper, Scissors. Built in Java. Uses Bayesian statistics.  Why Did I Build This? This project was built to showcase an AI technique that I learned from my AI course at the University of Massachusetts, Amherst.
How Did I Build This? This project is built in Java and uses simple Bayesian statistics to predict the player&amp;rsquo;s next move by calculating the probability the player&amp;rsquo;s next move based on all previous moves and based on his/her previous K moves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Won $6000 at Our First Hackathon</title>
      <link>/projects/fashion-filtr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/fashion-filtr/</guid>
      <description>Summary:  Won most creative use of Indico API at Hamp Hack 2017. Awarded $2000/team member in API credits. Teammates: Nischal Tamang and Phillip Michalowski.  Why Did We Build This? Usually, project ideas are either spawned from day-to-day life or assigned. However, since we decided to go to a hackathon without any preplanning, we had to come up with an idea on the spot. I think this usually works pretty well, because you don&amp;rsquo;t actually know what the prizes are and that is what usually dictates what you are building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$100,000 in Annual Revenue?!</title>
      <link>/projects/wesley-remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/wesley-remote/</guid>
      <description>Summary:  Big thanks to Dr. Rui Wang for funding me the neccessary resources to build this project!  More content coming soon!
The Problem The Solution v0.9 v1.0 The Software Buy one here! https://rayshobby.net/wordpress/opensprinkler-bee/
GitHub Repos:
Hardware: https://github.com/wesleytian/programmable-thermostat-hw
Firmware: https://github.com/wesleytian/thermostat-pro
Library: https://github.com/wesleytian/thermostat-pro-library
Mobile App: https://github.com/wesleytian/thermostat-pro-ionic</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Wesley has few official titles, but those don&amp;rsquo;t really describe what kind of person he is. Deep down, he just wants to be happy and free. But just like everybody else these days, he&amp;rsquo;s fallen under society&amp;rsquo;s spell to walk the common road of a quality education and a well-paying job.
Wesley&amp;rsquo;s goal is to eventually break free from that spell and gain the confidence to completely disregard both his own and other people&amp;rsquo;s judgments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>