<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2019s on Wesley Tian</title>
    <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2019s on Wesley Tian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Wesley Tian 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/22/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I turned 22. You could say I had a mini-quarter-life crisis. Most people retire at about age 60. That would put me at a third of the way through my career. It&amp;rsquo;s also not news that most people lay the foundations of their career in their 20s and early 30s, leading to an average peak in salary in their 40s.
 As Meg Jay, Ph.D., author of the Defining Decade says, &amp;ldquo;Eighty percent of life&amp;rsquo;s most defining moments take place by age thirty-five.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking the Resume</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/resume_tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/resume_tips/</guid>
      <description>1. Change your graduation date Imagine it&amp;rsquo;s currently the fall of 2016, you entered college in the fall 2015 and expect to graduate in spring 2019. A student who has enough credits to be a junior and puts down Dec. 2018 or May 2018 instead of May 2019 will give them an enormous edge in the resume screening process. This is because companies give special treatment to juniors because it is easier to convert them into full-time employees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Chapter</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/a-new-chapter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:21:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/a-new-chapter/</guid>
      <description>Like many of you, I spent this past break visiting family. Every few years or so, I make the effort to visit my dad&amp;rsquo;s side of the family in southern China. The last time I visited was over three years ago. During this time, I read countless articles about China&amp;rsquo;s insane economic development, advances in artificial intelligence, and a new social credit system that looks like something that came out of a Black Mirror episode.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>