<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Advice on Wesley Tian</title>
    <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/tags/advice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Advice on Wesley Tian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Wesley Tian 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wesleytian.github.io/tags/advice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A&#43; Résumé Tips</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/resume_tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/resume_tips/</guid>
      <description>1. Change your graduation date Imagine that you&amp;rsquo;re a college sophomore, but you have enough credits to graduate a year early. If you have enough credits to graduate early and you aren&amp;rsquo;t sure whether you will, it can be beneficial to put the earlier graduation date that would put you at junior standing.
Imagine it is currently the fall of 2016, you entered college in the fall 2015 and expect to graduate in spring 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice from a 4.00 GPA CS Freshman</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/advice/</guid>
      <description>1. Take classes with the course chair Taking classes with the course chair for courses with many sections such as Linear Algebra guarantees you a proficient teacher. They will most likely provide extra perks such as review sessions and review sheets. You are also guaranteed that the instructor will cover everything on the tests so you won&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about your professor omitting something.
I took Calculus I with the course chair during my freshman year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defined by Your Friends</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/friends/</guid>
      <description>Do your friends define who you are? Take a moment to ponder this thought.
Initially, the answer is no. You are yourself and there is nobody who can learn who you are by being around your friends. We are each too unique to be defined that way. Conversely, what if I told you that your friends shaped you? The people you&amp;rsquo;ve met and the conversations that you&amp;rsquo;ve had with your friends with nurtured and shaped the person you are today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Journey of a Thousand Miles Begins With a Single Step</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2015/steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2015/steps/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you don’t feel like going to the gym. For one reason or another, the real reason is that you’re too lazy and don’t feel like it. Don’t make excuses. But that’s another point.
Listen up, because I’m going to teach you a way that has made everything for me easier. It works for anything that you’ve been doing, but find yourself having trouble following through sometimes. Your brain works in strange ways and to appeal to your brain you have to take advantage of how your brain works.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>