<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>work on Wesley Tian</title>
    <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/tags/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in work on Wesley Tian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Wesley Tian 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wesleytian.github.io/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Land Your Dream Internship</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/internship/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2019/internship/</guid>
      <description>Here are five pieces of wisdom that I&amp;rsquo;ve gained from applying to hundreds of companies and speaking to hundreds of recruiters in the past four years. These tips aren&amp;rsquo;t just valuable for landing internship offers from the Big 4 (Facebook, Amazon, Microsoft, Google), but also at other companies.
1. Your Online Presence Matters More Than You Think Some people think that maintaining a personal website or LinkedIn is a waste of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a Better Software Engineer</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2018/swe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2018/swe/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently realized that the skills you learn as a software engineer (SWE) are disjoint from the skills that you learn in school. Below are some of my findings.
1. Nobody knows the answer, but it&amp;rsquo;s out there somewhere. It&amp;rsquo;s up to you and only you to figure it out. That&amp;rsquo;s what the company is paying you to do. Problem-solve.
When my internship first started, I shot questions at my mentor, full-timers, and other interns what seemed like every hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super Linux Warp Pipe</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2018/pipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2018/pipe/</guid>
      <description>Today at work I came across a problem that I managed to solve using multiple Linux pipes. What I needed to do to solve the problem was count the frequency of words existing between a certain context.
This is a simplified version of what the input looked like:
Where is the { FRUIT apple } ? Is the { PLANT tree } within the ground ? The { FRUIT banana } ate some { FRUIT banana } .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking an Inadequate Air Conditioner – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2017/ac_hack_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2017/ac_hack_2/</guid>
      <description>Click here for part 1.
After my professor and I created the prototype for the Remote Thermostat in, we worked on the printed circuit board layout using EAGLE.
Then we placed the order through a Chinese website and then waited for the board to be delivered.
https://opensprinkler.com/introducing-opensprinkler-bee-2-0-a-wifi-enabled-universal-sprinkler-controller/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking an Inadequate Air Conditioner – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/ac_hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/ac_hack/</guid>
      <description>It was scorching hot this summer in Amherst, Massachusetts. Especially because my room was on the second floor, the room temperature would often rise to over 100° F during midday. The house I stayed in didn&amp;rsquo;t have a central HVAC (heat-ventilation-air-conditioning) system built into the house so we opted for a window AC that could be inserted into the frame of the window and be plugged into the wall outlet for power.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>