<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2016s on Wesley Tian</title>
    <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2016s on Wesley Tian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Wesley Tian 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/advice/</guid>
      <description>1. Take classes with the course chair Taking classes with the course chair for courses with multiple sections such as Linear Algebra guarantees you a proficient teacher. They will most likely provide extra perks such as review sessions and review sheets. You are also guaranteed that the instructor will cover everything on the tests so you won&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about your professor omitting something.
I took Calculus I with the course chair my freshman year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking an Inadequate Air Conditioner</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/ac_hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/ac_hack/</guid>
      <description>It was scorching hot this summer in Amherst, Massachusetts. Especially because my room was on the second floor, the room temperature would often rise to over 100° F during midday. The house I stayed in didn&amp;rsquo;t have a central HVAC (heat-ventilation-air-conditioning) system built into the house so we opted for a window AC that could be inserted into the frame of the window and be plugged into the wall outlet for power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building My Own Amplifier</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/amp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/amp/</guid>
      <description>Why? What? and How?
As a music enthusiast, I&amp;rsquo;ve always been in the pursuit of the best sound replication devices. As I researched more and more about headphones and the amazing world of sound replication, I kept reading about these things called amps and DACs. For a long time, I simply ignored those terms as I felt that they were too advanced for just the average joe. They seemed too complicated and only for the professional studio recorders or niche audiophile market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiking the Half Dome</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/halfdome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/halfdome/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been nearly a whole year since I summited the half dome in Yosemite Valley National Park. One of my favorite hiking adventures of all time, below is the journal entry that I wrote after the hike.
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DhZQlaqzddg
A first-person POV video of the same path I took.
9/1/2015
It&amp;rsquo;s currently 3:28AM and I just really wanted to record my thoughts and experiences before I forget them. Up until now I have not had the chance to get on my computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Passion</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/passion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/passion/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve often been told that passion leads to success. It is one thing to hear a quote and another thing entirely to experience it firsthand. This summer, I was hired as an intern by Ray (Rui) Wang, a computer science professor at the University of Massachusetts Amherst as well as the founder of Ray&amp;rsquo;s Hobby and OpenSprinkler. During these three months, I learned a handful of technical skills as well as professional skills such as problem solving and communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Independence</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/independence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/independence/</guid>
      <description>The following is a story about my dad&amp;rsquo;s iron fist and how he guided me to complete independence at a tender age of 18 and what I did about it. &amp;ldquo;When you turn 18, you&amp;rsquo;re on your own,&amp;rdquo; my dad had told me time and time again ever since I was old enough to begin worrying about college. He had told me that he would support me financially enough only to satisfy my school tuition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Don&#39;t Have a Passion. Yet.</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/passionless/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/passionless/</guid>
      <description>What is your passion? I was asked this question by my professor nonchalantly while having a light conversation. It seemed like a simple question at first. However, after deeply thinking about it, I realized that I did not have an answer. I answered with &amp;ldquo;well, I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about a lot of things. I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about the environment, and about other things.&amp;rdquo; Compared to him, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t even really passionate about the environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living with a Professor</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/professor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/professor/</guid>
      <description>My freshmen chapter ends here, and a new chapter begins. Today, I moved in with an associate professor from the Computer Science department at UMass Amherst. I will be working for him for the next 4 months. He runs an open-source hardware business that produces programmable sprinklers for people. This opportunity is a godsend; the fact that I am making money is crumbs compared to what else I may gain from this invaluable experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defined by Your Friends</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/friends/</guid>
      <description>Do your friends define who you are? Take a moment to ponder this thought.
Initially, the answer is no. You are yourself and there is nobody who can learn who you are by just being around your friends. We are each too unique to be defined that way. Conversely, what if I told you that you were shaped by your friends? You were nurtured by the people you&amp;rsquo;ve met and seen, the conversations and events you shared with your friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiences vs. Possessions</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/experience/</guid>
      <description>Departure. You don&amp;rsquo;t really feel the emotions of leaving a place that has been your home until about 4 days before the date of departure. Everyone talks about it long before that phase like they are sad and sentimental, but you don&amp;rsquo;t really feel it until it&amp;rsquo;s right upon you.
Starting yesterday, I&amp;rsquo;ve begun to feel it. All the emotions slowly building up, in addition to the fact that you are physically also preparing yourself, packing, and going through all of your belongings, things that you haven&amp;rsquo;t touched in years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>