<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Story on Wesley Tian</title>
    <link>/tags/story/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Story on Wesley Tian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:14:49 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/story/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a Better SWE</title>
      <link>/posts/swe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/swe/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently learned some interesting things about being a software engineer which you don&amp;rsquo;t really learn in school at all. The skills you learn as a SWE are totally disjoint from the set of skills that you gain from your classes.
1. Nobody knows the answer. But it&amp;rsquo;s out there somewhere. It&amp;rsquo;s up to you and only you to figure it out. That&amp;rsquo;s what the company is paying you to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another New Site?</title>
      <link>/posts/another-new-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/another-new-site/</guid>
      <description>So, it seems like every few months I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling discontent with my personal website, thus prompting me to rehaul my website over and over again. This frequent rehauling can be boiled down to two reasons.
 I have never really felt satisfied with the overall design and aesthetic of my personal website.
 I haven&amp;rsquo;t made up my mind about starting my blog back up again or not.
  I&amp;rsquo;ve been toying around with Jekyll and Bootstrap recently, and then I found Hugo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosting Hugo Using GitHub</title>
      <link>/posts/a-better-hugo-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-better-hugo-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>In this short tutorial, you will be creating two repositories, one that will store your Hugo source files, and one that will store the files neccessary to view your website. The website repo is called public and will be inside of your source repository. This will be done by using a git submodule.
This guide requires you to have git installed, a Hugo website that you can easily clone from it&amp;rsquo;s github repo, and a GitHub account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saving Lives with Machine Learning</title>
      <link>/projects/gvhd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/gvhd/</guid>
      <description>Summary:
 Work in progress. Teammates: Shengpu Tang, Dr. Jenna Wiens  Why Did I Build This? How Did I Build This? What Did I Learn From Building This? Operating Instructions: More updates coming soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning with Residual Blocks</title>
      <link>/projects/residual/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/residual/</guid>
      <description>Summary:  Lead team of undergraduate and graduate students to replicate results of the Deep Residual Learning for Image Recognition research paper. Team: Cory Laban  Why Did I Build This? How Did I Build This? What Did I Learn From Building This? https://arxiv.org/pdf/1512.03385.pdf
More updates coming soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Own Cryptocurrency</title>
      <link>/projects/westcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/westcoin/</guid>
      <description>Summary:  Cryptocurrency built in Selenium on the Ethereum blockchain. Blockchain @ Michigan Workshop. WesTCoin is currently private and the exchange rate is 1 WesTCoin ~ 1 Ethereum.  Why Did I Build This? The Blockchain @ Michigan club at the University of Michigan was hosting a workshop to teach people how to create their own cryptocurrencies on the Ethereum blockchain. As as a former blockchain and cryptocurrency enthusiast, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t turn down this great opportunity to attend this workshop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Machine Learning Competition</title>
      <link>/projects/assistments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/assistments/</guid>
      <description>More updates coming soon!
Summary:
 https://sites.google.com/view/assistmentsdatamining/home?authuser=0 Placed 3rd out of 74 research teams. Technologies: Python Teammates: Samuel Tenka  Why Did I Build This? How Did I Build This? What Did I Learn From Building This? Operating Instructions: Source: https://sites.google.com/view/assistmentsdatamining/winners-of-the-2017-competion</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Presented to 3 Senior Vice Presidents of Fidelity Investments</title>
      <link>/projects/fid-hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/fid-hack/</guid>
      <description> Summary:  Helped build an internal interviewer-interviewee scheduler. 6 competing teams. Teammates: Mike Super, Akhil Yerra, etc.  Why Did I Build This? How Did I Build This? What Did I Learn From Building This? Operating Instructions: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Won $6000 at Our First Hackathon</title>
      <link>/projects/fashion-filtr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/fashion-filtr/</guid>
      <description>Summary:  Won most creative use of Indico API at Hamp Hack 2017. Awarded $2000/team member in API credits. Teammates: Nischal Tamang and Phillip Michalowski.  Why Did We Build This? Usually, project ideas are either spawned from day-to-day life or assigned. However, since we decided to go to a hackathon without any preplanning, we had to come up with an idea on the spot. I think this usually works pretty well, because you don&amp;rsquo;t actually know what the prizes are and that is what usually dictates what you are building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baby Tracker</title>
      <link>/projects/where-is-my-baby/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/where-is-my-baby/</guid>
      <description> More updates coming soon!
Summary:
 Parse Baby Berk&amp;rsquo;s Twitter feed to gather current location of the food truck and display it on a map. Teammates: Phillip Michalowski and Nischal Tamang  Why Did I Build This? How Did I Build This? What Did I Learn From Building This? Operating Instructions: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A CSP Parser for AISpace</title>
      <link>/projects/csv-xml/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/csv-xml/</guid>
      <description>Summary:
 This script turns a CSV file into a XML file that can be imported into AIspace&amp;rsquo;s Consistency Based CSP Solver. Built using Python.  Why Did I Build This? How Did I Build This? What Did I Learn From Building This? Operating Instructions: The Consistency Based CSP Solver: http://www.aispace.org/downloads.shtml GitHub Repo: https://github.com/wesleytian/csv-xml-csp
More updates coming soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$100,000 in Annual Revenue?!</title>
      <link>/projects/wesley-remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/wesley-remote/</guid>
      <description>Summary:  Big thanks to Dr. Rui Wang for funding me the neccessary resources to build this project!  More content coming soon!
The Problem The Solution v0.9 v1.0 The Software Buy one here! https://rayshobby.net/wordpress/opensprinkler-bee/
GitHub Repos:
Hardware: https://github.com/wesleytian/programmable-thermostat-hw
Firmware: https://github.com/wesleytian/thermostat-pro
Library: https://github.com/wesleytian/thermostat-pro-library
Mobile App: https://github.com/wesleytian/thermostat-pro-ionic</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>