<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>project on Wesley Tian</title>
    <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/tags/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in project on Wesley Tian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Wesley Tian 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:14:49 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wesleytian.github.io/tags/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosting Hugo Using GitHub</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2018/a-better-hugo-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:14:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2018/a-better-hugo-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>In this short tutorial, you will be creating two repositories, one that will store your Hugo source files, and one that will store the files neccessary to view your website. The website repo is called public and will be inside of your source repository. This will be done by using a git submodule.
This guide requires you to have git installed, a Hugo website that you can easily clone from it&amp;rsquo;s github repo, and a GitHub account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking an Inadequate Air Conditioner – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2017/ac_hack_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2017/ac_hack_2/</guid>
      <description>Click here for part 1.
After my professor and I created the prototype for the Remote Thermostat in, we worked on the printed circuit board layout using EAGLE.
Then we placed the order through a Chinese website and then waited for the board to be delivered.
https://opensprinkler.com/introducing-opensprinkler-bee-2-0-a-wifi-enabled-universal-sprinkler-controller/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking an Inadequate Air Conditioner – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/ac_hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/ac_hack/</guid>
      <description>GitHub Repository: https://github.com/wesleytian/thermostat-pro
It was scorching hot this summer in Amherst, Massachusetts. Especially because my room was on the second floor, the room temperature would often rise to over 100° F during midday. The house I stayed in didn&amp;rsquo;t have a central HVAC (heat-ventilation-air-conditioning) system built into the house so we opted for a window AC that could be inserted into the frame of the window and be plugged into the wall outlet for power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building My Own Headphone Amp</title>
      <link>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/amp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wesleytian.github.io/2016/amp/</guid>
      <description>The finished Objective2 headphone amp
As a music enthusiast, I&amp;rsquo;ve always been in the pursuit of the best sound replication devices. As I researched more and more about headphones and the amazing world of sound replication, I kept reading about these things called amps and DACs (digital-to-analag converters). For a long time, I simply ignored those terms as I felt that they were too advanced for the average Joe. They seemed too complicated and only for the professional studio recorders or niche audiophile market.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>